39

The Battle of Hogwarts

Harry and his friends decided to take advantage of the unusually mild spring weather one Saturday, and lugged their revision out to the lake. They weren’t alone in this, as many of their classmates were also enjoying the sun, even if it wasn’t a Hogsmeade weekend.

The only noticeable absence was the Slytherins. Evidently some of them had gotten together and decided to test Professor Slughorn’s resolve in Potions class. Most of yesterday’s sabotage attempts failed, but it was still enough to set the older wizard’s walrus-like moustache to quivering. Nearly half of the third-year students in their class received detentions, and Ginny reported much the same happened in second-year Potions. It was enough to provoke the Head of Slytherin to announce during the feast that night that the entire house would be attending a compulsory house meeting all day on Saturday.

Even Ron was impressed.

While Harry was sorry they were giving Slughorn grief over his enforced détente with the other houses, it also meant he and his friends didn’t need to watch their backs as much when they were away from the castle. Harry supposed it was a legacy of the Malfoy influence on the house, and wondered if there was any way to defuse it before things got worse. He hoped that if he and the others only responded when attacked, the others might get the hint, but he wasn’t going to hold his breath.

Sean led his men carefully through the heavy woods. According to their informant, the entrance to the British Army research facility was disguised by what looked like a bunch of medieval enthusiasts, the crazy buggers that liked to get together on a weekend and pretend they still lived in the Middle Ages. Their little pretend village let the government move people and supplies in and out of the base without raising anyone’s curiosity.

As they skirted the edge of a clearing, Sean paused and checked the target area with his field glasses. The recreationists’ village, Hogsmeade, was still hidden in the valley, but the ‘abandoned’ castle that loomed behind it was visible in the morning sun. He peered at it for a long moment. The drafty-looking ruins gave him a chill, and not just because of what he knew lay beneath it. But he swallowed his fear. If what they’d been told was correct, exposing the technology the British had developed would draw world-wide attention. If their way truly was the will of the people, then what need would they have for mind-control technology? International sympathy for their struggle could force concessions impossible a year ago… Now they just had to go in there and take the prize.

With a sigh, he stowed the field glasses and re-settled his rucksack. The path they’d been instructed to take was steep and winding, but he’d been warned that he had to stick to it exactly or risk disaster. He obeyed, despite his aching legs, having no desire to run into British commandos on manoeuvres.

And so Sean led his men around the edges of the Acromantula range as they worked their way toward Hogsmeade, unaware of just how gruesome a death he’d avoided by sticking to the plan.

It wasn’t hard to find a sunny spot for the Gryffindor Six to spread out their books and sprawl on the warm grass. It was uncommonly warm down by the lake, feeling more like end of term than start of spring.

Harry had some difficulty keeping his eyes open as he read through his transfiguration book. Sure, he knew the general principles, but he still had to refresh himself on the details if he wanted to avoid Professor McGonagall’s ire. It was worse that he’d worked so hard to establish a reputation for studying hard – she wouldn’t accept anything less than his best work. So here he was, trying to re-memorize the nineteen special cases for the Laws of Similarity. If anything, having an easier time understanding them made it paradoxically harder to stay awake and not let his mind wander.

After he nearly stuck his nose in the binding, Ginny noticed his ‘difficulties’. In response, she shifted around a little so the toe of her shoe lay near his calf. The next time his eyes drooped, she gave him a little nudge. He looked up, a little startled, but her eyes were firmly focused on her Potions textbook. Hermione gave Harry a questioning look, but he just waved it off.

After that, it became a bit of a game. Ginny never once looked directly at him, yet whenever his attention began to waver, she gave him a subtle nudge. After a while, trying to catch her looking was far more engrossing than his transfiguration revision. But even if it was a distraction, it kept him awake and safe from the Wrath of Granger.

The trail ended as the map promised, right on the verge of the little village. Sean cracked a grin as his team skirted around the lake, heading for the ruined iron gates. He glanced over at his mates, and saw faces as drawn with tension as his own. They’d been together a long time, so no words were needed. It was time.

Madam Rosmerta sighed as she swept out the entryway to her pub. She normally liked her job. Running The Three Broomsticks was her passion, but lately the shine had gone off of it. The cordon of Dementors those fools in the Ministry stationed around Hogwarts and Hogsmeade were not what she considered good neighbours. The soul-sucking monsters could bleed the cheer out of the brightest spring day, much like this one. While her sales of hot chocolate were up, everything else was down.

Worse, the Hogsmeade weekends were running light. Many Hogwarts students didn’t want to step foot outside the wards and risk running afoul of the damn wraiths. Not that she blamed the poor dears after what the nasty things had done at the Quidditch match. But that meant her normally busiest weekends of the year were instead rather anaemic. It was much the same for her fellow business folk, with only Honeydukes doing better than usual – and that only because everyone was eating chocolate to ward off the lingering effects of the Dementors. And poor Ambrosius wasn’t seeing any profit from it – not after offering a steep discount on chocolate to his neighbours just so they could stay in business.

Fudge hadn’t set foot in Hogsmeade this year, which was a good thing for him. If Rosmerta laid eyes on him, he’d find his Minister’s discount rescinded and her wand in his face. Wouldn’t surprise her if the whole town wanted to lynch the silly bugger by this point. Especially with Harry Potter, of all people, asking why Sirius Black never got a trial. Fishy, that whole business.

Sighing at the foolishness of it all, she stopped suddenly as she saw a strangely dressed group of men slip behind the train station along the lake shore. They almost looked like… Muggles? But what would they be doing here?

Then she felt the air around her chill. Rosmerta’s hand went to her mouth. The Dementors had sensed them and slipped free of their handlers again. Those poor men didn’t stand a chance.

She dropped her worn out old broom and pulled out her wand. Her Patronus wasn’t very strong, but she and others had been practising steadily since the Ministry went stupid. It was one thing if The Boy Who Lived made a Patronus bigger than the Knight Bus, but they’d also heard that Hogwarts was teaching second year students how to make a corporeal Patronus. That left no excuses for the rest of them.

As she took off down the path that led past the train station to the gates, her breath frosted in front of her as masses of Dementors moved toward the gates. Behind them, she could see the puffing forms of their Ministry ‘handlers’, shooting silver sparks from their wands and trying to get their charges under control again.

Useless, the lot of them.

She wasn’t as young as she used to be, but she still kept up a good pace all the way around the lake. Those Muggles must have been particularly fit, as they were already to the gates as she caught sight of them again. The poor dears were definitely feeling the Dementors, even if they couldn’t see them. The stragglers of their group were sinking to the ground, holding themselves and shivering, the others looking around wildly. One of them saw the Ministry wizards and pulled out an odd sort of wand. It let out a series of bangs, but the man’s hands were shaking so badly that he dropped it shortly before crumpling to the ground.

The wizards he’d been pointing toward slowed down and began casting shielding charms. No one had noticed her yet, but Rosmerta wondered if she should do the same. The Muggles appeared to be dangerous.

At this point, the lead Muggle spun around wildly, watching his mates collapse to the ground. Rosmerta’s stomach turned. She knew there was no way she could get there before at least some of them were Kissed by the approaching mob. Maybe it was a kindness that Muggles couldn’t see them.

Then the Muggle took a cloth-covered parcel off of his back. He pulled something out of it, perhaps a string, and then hurled it at the Hogwarts Gates as he dove to the ground…

Sean growled as the last of his men fell to the invisible, odourless gas. A coward’s weapon if there ever was one. He’d been warned of the possibility if they were detected, but they had made it close enough to the ruined-looking gate. If he could take it out before it dispensed more of the nerve agent, the gas might dissipate in time for his men to recover before they were captured.

Following the road had seemed like madness, but braving a minefield was worse.

His hands shook with palsy as he armed the home-made satchel charge. Bloody nerve agents. Nasty business. But he managed to pull the cord for the impact fuse, and his arm was still strong enough to sling the messenger bag directly at one of the winged boars. He dove to the ground and covered his head.

Then everything went white, and he knew no more.

Madam Rosmerta picked herself up off the ground, her ears ringing. There had been a loud noise and something like a giant’s hand had pushed her to the ground. Once she got her bearings, she looked toward the gate.

It was shattered – twisted fragments of metal and shards of stone littered the ground where it had been. Most of the pieces seemed to have been blown inward, onto the Hogwarts grounds. But while the Muggles sprawled on the ground had only minor wounds, the ones she could see the faces of were staring glassily upward with vacant eyes.

Her stomach clenched as she realized they’d all been Kissed by the hungry Dementors.

At that point, the fading chill impinged on her awareness. The Dementors were gone, leaving only the horrific soulless refuse of their feeding. And since she was still alive, she knew which way they had gone.

One of the Ministry wizards asked if she was all right. She rounded on him. “Of course I’m not all right. Those things have gone into Hogwarts!”

It was a lesson that Harry hadn’t thought he’d forgotten – just how quickly things could go to utter hell. But the time he’d spent in the past had, despite all his expectations, taken the edge off of his dread.

He even ignored the echoing bang, knowing the Twins were likely mucking about with their fireworks again.

So it was that he also dismissed the first chill that ran down his spine as he studied Transfiguration, thinking it was just Mother Nature reminding them they were in Scotland after all. But the second chill, accompanied by just the faintest whisper of his mum’s screams, snapped his head up so quickly a muscle in his neck spasmed.

Harry shot to his feet, his book tumbling across Ron’s back and raising a muffled oath. He ignored his friend as his eyes widened behind his glasses.

Coming around the lake, roughly following the path from the gates, was a bloody horde of Dementors. Too many to count. Harry swore he felt the sun dim on his back as he watched one of his worst nightmares come to life. He could already feel their hunger as they glided along the grass, withering it as they passed and riming the lake shore with ice.

Many generations will have defining moments, instants of time that mark everyone that experienced them. Later in their lives, those that survive will speak of what they were doing when a beloved monarch passed on, when a war was declared, or other such watershed moments in the passage of history.

Some few would speak of what they were doing when the Dementors overran Hogwarts, and Harry Potter shouted.

“Sonorus,” Harry whispered, his heart pounding in his chest. The tip of his wand was uncomfortably warm as it tapped his Adam’s apple, but it barely registered on his awareness. “Get to the castle, now!” he shouted with every breath in his body. He ignored the stabbing pain in his chest as well.

Later, the inhabitants of Hogsmeade, which was in roughly the direction Harry was facing, would find their North-facing windows, the ones with a view of the castle, crazed with tiny cracks.

Harry released the spell immediately. Stunned students were moving now, some running, others stumbling, but all of them moving toward the castle, possessions forgotten in the mad rush for survival.

But it wasn’t nearly fast enough.

The terror of their sudden appearance seemed to galvanize the hellish creatures, sharpening their appetites as the air chilled further and the day seemed to turn overcast in moments. Harry didn’t even want to contemplate the amount of power needed to do that as more than a hundred starving psychovores bore down on a crowd of schoolchildren.

And they were accelerating.

Harry gritted his teeth as his mum’s pleas blended into Ginny’s voice, screaming in pain as it became incoherent. The wet bleating of the torn and mangled body he found after the massacre. For an instant, he pictured Draco and Voldemort’s noseless face and his horror turned to rage. His magic responded eagerly and the pains in his chest returned. But his wand was almost vibrating in his hand. He looked for his happy thought.

That will never happen. Ever!

Harry Potter raised his wand.

And he thought of what happened in the Chamber of Secrets.

They forgave me, for everything I ever did. I love them and I will never let you have them!

“Expecto Patronum!” As he leveled his wand, the giant silver stag charged out of thin air. It was a good bit bigger than he remembered from the Quidditch match, and seemed to glow all the brighter for the rapidly dimming sun. Harry almost lost his focus on the spell when he felt the thud of its hooves on the ground transmitted to his own feet. But neither his rage nor his joy were having any of that, overly corporeal Patronus or not.

Harry almost cursed aloud as a few students slowed to watch the silver stag pass them, bearing down on the Dementors like the wrath of an entire pantheon. It smashed square into the middle of the horde, tossing them with its antlers like ragdolls, kicking and stomping like a force of nature.

But there were so many… and as Harry’s Patronus tore at the middle, the Dementors to either side edged around the melee, still intent on their fleeing prey. Harry had slowed them, nothing more, and his Patronus was starting to slow down as it vented its wrath on the swarm. It wouldn’t last forever.

But other silver forms were racing forward to stall the flankers. He recognized the solid forms of his friends’ Patronuses, along with those of some of the older students in the duelling club.

Harry let out a shaky breath as the titanic stag faded, leaving several Dementors twitching and heaving on the ground. It had broken their charge, but now they needed to contain the fiends while the students escaped. The castle had its own protections, and at the least solid walls to keep them at a distance. He recast his Patronus, and glanced quickly at his friends.

They looked scared, but determined. He almost asked them to head back to the castle, but he knew that was a lost cause before he even started. More likely they’d hex him in the back for suggesting it. “We need to spread out,” he panted instead, “keep them from getting around us. Ron, Hermione, go left fifty paces. Neville, Luna, go right. Fall back before you get too tired or I’ll have Rita make up lies about your love-life.”

He tried to sound confident, but the tightness in his chest made it hard. Ginny eyed him as he turned back, but didn’t say anything.

The six of them fell into an easy rhythm as they spread apart, giving proof that all those training exercises were worth something. Everyone would cast on Harry’s mark, giving the Dementors no easy way around, and together they would push the foul things back a few paces. This gave heart to the students with less robust constitutions, and they began to make their way back to the castle with better speed.

But each wave of silver Patronuses took a noticeable amount of energy from the casters, and struck the horde of Dementors with a little less fervour. Soon, the retreat had turned back into an advance, albeit a slow one. Still, Harry was proud of his friends. Most of the Duelling Association members that knew the charm couldn’t repeat it more than twice.

And every moment bought more time for the students to escape.

During a quick glance backward, Harry saw some adults fighting forward through the press in the courtyard, but the chaos must have been incredible. If things didn’t change quickly… this wasn’t a sustainable situation.

Something had to give, and it finally did.

Off to Harry’s left, a trio of first year Hufflepuff girls were frozen in fear. He couldn’t honestly blame them for being scared out of their minds. But blamelessness wouldn’t save their souls from consumption if they were caught.

Instead, someone who was often considered an odd duck in the ‘House of the Brave’ was proving otherwise. Hermione’s otter Patronus seemed to be everywhere at once, trying to keep the Dementors away from the terrified girls. She ignored Ron when he tried to get her to pull back with the others, despite how her wand arm was shaking. When the girls were the only students in front of them, and the Dementors not far off, they both abandoned the Patronus charm and instead summoned the weeping girls.

Hermione snagged two, and with a nice bit of wand-work, banished them both back towards the relative safety of the castle without either girl slowing down. Ron opted instead to catch his in his arms and they knocked heads for a moment. He got her back on her feet and running toward the castle, but it was too late.

The bushy-haired witch had overextended herself, magically and otherwise. When she turned back toward the Dementors, they were too close and she was too tired to cast another Patronus. Her hand trembled as she slowly sank to her knees.

Harry snarled as he watched this disaster unfold, and immediately re-cast his Patronus, ignoring the spots that swam in front of his eyes for a moment. The slightly diminished stag loped toward his friends, but it wasn’t moving nearly as fast… and the Dementors were right on top of them.

Most of the Dementors moving to encircle Ron and Hermione shied away from the silver stag, but the lead wraith was too close to be denied. A bony hand reached out and grabbed Hermione’s hair, forcing her head back and her face up as its hooded head descended.

With a cry of despair, Ron dropped his wand and barrelled into the pair, knocking the dazed Hermione aside as he grappled with the Dementor.

Harry almost lost control of his own Patronus.

A wave of silver forms was emerging from the school now, giving Neville and Luna a breather. A silver phoenix circled around Ron and Hermione’s position, helping Harry’s tired stag force the others back. But their leader was still struggling with Ron. Neither seemed likely to give up, until the Dementor got both hands around Ron’s throat and slowly began to force his head back. Harry hesitated. They were too close together. Any spell he could think of was more likely to hit Ron, and summoning him could easily break his neck in the Dementor’s grip.

Then there was a burst of flame, and a real phoenix joined its silver clone. Phoenix song soared over the battlefield, giving heart to the students fleeing toward the castle.

And still the Dementor moved to kiss Ron and consume his soul.

Horrified, Harry raged at how his friend’s loyalty was to be repaid. Fawkes made a dive at the Dementor, but didn’t claw at the monster – it already had something in its talons. Something it left behind as it climbed again, trilling its song.

Ragged fabric?

Even as his stag faded, Harry used the Sonorus charm again. “Ron! Reach into the hat!” He ignored the taste of blood in the back of his mouth as his voice started to go hoarse at the end.

Ron flailed at the fabric covering his face and temporarily blocking the Dementor’s attempts to kiss him. As it slipped away and the hood descended the final time, he got his right hand inside and it emerged with something heavy.

Something silver.

Something glittering with rubies the size of eggs.

The Dementor let out a horrific screech as Ronald Weasley thrust the Sword of Gryffindor into its chest. It let go of his throat, throwing him back, but Ron held onto the sword and it ripped loose of the Dementor’s cloak with a burst of sickly green light. The sword flashed, shining far brighter than it should in the diminished sunlight. The Dementor fell back, writhing as silver light spilled from the rent in its cloak. It let out a deafening shriek as the light grew brighter. Ron staggered back, but managed to keep his feet and avoided tripping on Hermione. She in turn gripped her wand as she struggled to her feet.

The shrieking reached a fever pitch as the Dementors on the left flank fell back in disarray. Then it cut off abruptly as the empty robes collapsed to the ground.

Ron looked down at the glittering sword. He looked up at the Dementors.

Then he took a step forward.

“Come and have a go, if you think you’re hard enough,” he yelled, “you soul-sucking bastards!”

The Dementors of Azkaban withdrew before the righteous fury of a thirteen-year-old with a sword, an ancient artefact that had tasted their mortality and found it good.

Harry looked over at Ginny, who seemed to be equally speechless.

The Battle of Hogwarts: Dementors Run Amok!

Ministry Disavows Any Knowledge of Dementor Betrayal!

Heir of Gryffindor Attending Hogwarts?

Harry grimaced at the aftertaste from the thick and clingy potion he’d just choked down. Madam Pomfrey was quite adamant that he take the full series if he wanted to avoid permanent damage to his voice. Given the large numbers of students needing chocolate and/or calming draughts, it was decided to treat each house within its own common room.

That left Harry as the only person stuck in the hospital wing. For strained vocal cords, no less. He felt so ridiculous, all things considered, that he might have snuck out while Madam Pomfrey was visiting the houses, if she hadn’t done something so ruthless, so diabolical, that he was still shocked.

She’d put Ginny in charge of him. And given her his wand.

With a few choice words about permanent scarring to his vocal cords, his friend proved more than willing to hold him at wand-point. She even offered to stun him between dosage times if he didn’t think he could remain quiet.

There was simply no justice. At all.

So he was reduced to sitting quietly, reading the special edition of the Daily Prophet, and trying to ignore the foul aftertaste of medicinal potions. At least Rita appeared to be having fun.

…Ministry sources claimed that their handlers from the Department of Magical Law Enforcement had been temporarily incapacitated by mild potion introduced into their lunch-time tea. However, this reporter is left wondering how a handful of wizards was expected to control dozens of heretofore unkillable wraiths that would view them as a food source. As with many decisions made by the Fudge Administration, common sense seems to have little to do with it!

At least someone appeared to be having a worse day than he was. It was a wonder the special edition hadn’t spontaneously combusted from an excess of righteous indignation…

It was after Saturday dinner that Harry was finally released from Madam Pomfrey’s clutches. He wasn’t sure who reported him straining his voice, and at that point he was too tired to care. He didn’t think he’d win that argument anyway.

It wasn’t that he’d tried to hurt himself… his magic was just a bit too… enthusiastic. Understandable, given the panic he’d felt when he realized their situation. But still worrisome.

When he and Ginny moved through the Fat Lady’s portrait, they were engulfed in a wall of sound. It seemed like everyone in their house was in the common room, speaking at once. As they picked their way through the crowd, they realized that the focus of the room was on the couch where Ron, Hermione, Neville, and Luna were under siege. From the way Ron was gripping the sword in his lap, “under siege” might not have been just a metaphor. His eyes were a bit wild, and Harry didn’t doubt that Hermione’s hand on his elbow was one of the few things keeping him from making a break for it.

Harry let out a quiet sigh and pushed through the crowd. When he finally emerged into the cleared space around the couch, he flopped into one of the squashy chairs next to it with deliberate nonchalance. “McGonagall’s going to have my guts for garters if I fall behind in Transfiguration. I don’t suppose anyone picked up our books, did they?”

Everyone stared at him. Except Ginny, who was smiling slightly as she sat down in the other chair. From the way Hermione’s mouth dropped open, he knew that, for once, he’d caught her not worrying about their school work. Harry felt like jumping up and performing a quick victory dance.

Ron let out a snort.

“Madam Pince,” Hermione began, giving Ron a very small nudge, “charmed all the books left lying on the ground and then gathered them up in the Great Hall before the sun set that day. That was very thoughtful of her, and I was able to recover everyone’s possessions.”

Colin Creevey let out a laugh. “Like you’d have to study again after all that!” he said.

Harry turned to look at the second-year boy with a raised eyebrow, even as Hermione’s glare shut him up. “What is that supposed to mean?” he asked.

“Oh, honestly,” Hermione answered with a huff. “He thinks the professors won’t dare give Ron failing marks because he’s the Heir of Gryffindor!”

Harry was willing to bet that his eyes bugged out as he digested that tid-bit of information. “Mister Weasley,” he said after a moment, in a fair imitation of McGonagall’s clipped classroom voice, “in light of your… heritage… I will accept nothing less than your best work in my class. Is that understood?”

That got a few laughs, and a rueful blush from Ron, but with the clearing of a single throat the laughter died away with unnatural speed. Harry felt a chill go down the back of his neck. He slumped and put his face in his hands. “She walked up right behind me as I said that, didn’t she?”

Ginny nodded, her hair looking even brighter than normal in contrast to her now-pale face.

“Your grasp of the obvious is as keen as your gift for imitations, Mister Potter,” his Head of House said, her voice coming from behind his chair. He flinched in spite of himself. “You and your friends are to accompany me to the Headmaster’s office.”

No one needed to ask which ‘friends’ she meant.

The long march from Gryffindor Tower was as silent as it was uncomfortable. Finally, Harry, ignoring the counsel of his common sense, had to break the silence. “Er, you know, it wasn’t meant as an insult, professor. I mean, I don’t think you’d ever stop expecting any of us to work hard. In your class. No matter what else we’ve done. You know…”

His voice trailed off as he peered up at the stern witch’s face. Something he’d seen out of the corner of his eye made him speed up a little until he could see her face better.

There was no doubt. She was actually smiling a little. Finally she spoke. “I never said that I considered your words insulting, Mister Potter. Only that you had a fine grasp of the obvious.” Her tone was as brisk as ever, but now he could hear an undertone of amusement as well.

“I should have stayed in the hospital wing,” he muttered under his breath.

Harry’s disgruntlement persisted only as long as it took to ascend the stairs behind the gargoyle. The door to the Headmaster’s office opened onto a scene of utter chaos. Harry could see Mrs. Weasley’s hair, and a flash of Mr. Lovegood’s thinning pate, but the crowd of adults was just as muddled as the wave of sound that washed over them.

“What is the meaning of this bedlam?” Professor McGonagall demanded, her voice cutting right through the babble.

Harry couldn’t help but note that most of the people in the office immediately snapped to attention. It didn’t take long for the Headmaster to conjure chairs for all of the adults, including, he was surprised to see, Mr. and Mrs. Granger. In fact, the parents of all the Gryffindor Six were in attendance, along with Madam Bones and Kingsley Shacklebolt.

It still took a little while to get everyone settled down. Mrs. Weasley, er, Molly, had to reassure herself that all three of her children really were all right. It still gave Harry a lump in his throat at how she automatically included him in her count. Hermione’s parents were a bit more restrained, but a question he’d always had regarding Hermione’s habits was answered when Mrs. Granger squeezed her daughter hard enough to force a squeak out of his bushy-haired friend.

With everyone sitting, including their Head of House, Professor Dumbledore cleared his throat. “My apologies for the delay, but I did not wish to hold this meeting until all of the parents of the students involved were present. I was also threatened with dire consequences by Madam Pomfrey if I allowed Mr. Potter to make use of his voice before she had cleared him to speak.”

Harry ignored any reddening of his face (that was probably purely coincidental) as some of the adults chuckled.

As the parents of the students ‘closest to the action’, they were being debriefed first. Harry suspected the Headmaster and Madam Bones were also seeking to gauge their reactions as indicators of how the other parents would take the news.

“As best we can tell,” Madam Bones began, “the Hogwarts wards were disrupted by a powerful Muggle explosive device being detonated in close proximity to one of the anchors. Designed to repel any known forms of magical attack when the castle was built, someone figured out that a sufficiently powerful non-magical explosion could shift the anchor out of alignment.”

“The Muggle weapons of the era when Hogwarts was constructed could never have accomplished such a feat,” Professor Flitwick added. “During the repairs we made alterations to all the ward foci to ensure such a tactic never works again.” He still looked aggrieved that he hadn’t anticipated the flaw that let the Dementors onto the grounds.

“That’s all very good,” Mr. Granger spoke up after a moment. “But who wanted to bomb a school full of children?” Harry was quite sure he didn’t imagine the undercurrent of anger he heard in the man’s voice.

“The bodies and the surviving attackers… well, what’s left of them, anyway, were identified by our colleagues at Scotland Yard,” Madam Bones replied. “What we’re having problems understanding is the motivation.”

“The men involved in the attack were members of the Provisional Irish Republican Army,” Shacklebolt added.

“What the bloody hell were they doing over here?” Mr. Granger demanded.

“We have no idea,” Madam Bones admitted. “But the repercussions of this…”

“I fear these men were beguiled to their deaths,” Dumbledore said quietly. “I won’t ask that you mourn the men who put your children at risk, but I believe they were manipulated into doing this for a reason. Arthur?”

“The Muggle Protection Act,” Mr. Weasley answered in an aggrieved tone. “Once it becomes public knowledge that Muggles attacked Hogwarts, it’ll be repealed before the sun sets.”

Dumbledore nodded. “A likely goal,” he agreed, stroking his beard, “and one I think we can all agree should be thwarted.”

“Thwarted how?” Mr. Lovegood asked.

“Well, fortunately, due to the quick actions of your children, a tragedy was averted,” Dumbledore said, directing a beneficent smile toward the assembled students. “If any students had been Kissed, I doubt there would be any way to prevent a full inquiry and disclosure – which was likely the aim of whoever set this into motion. Instead, we have a bit of excitement over the weekend, and the revelation of some surprising aspects of young Mr. Weasley’s heritage.”

“So you want me to bury the story, do you?” Mr. Lovegood asked, his normally unfocused expression going hard for a moment. “You know that Rita Skeeter is practically burning Fudge in effigy over at the Prophet.”

“It has come to my attention that our Mr. Potter has some small influence on the woman,” Dumbledore replied smoothly. “Perhaps he can prevail upon her to… focus on other aspects of current events?”

Harry didn’t even bother to glance at McGonagall. He expected her to share her concerns about his press manipulations when they were on the outs. “I’m not sure what I can offer her to get her to give up such a juicy story,” he said dryly.

“Perhaps an introduction to the newly discovered Heir of Gryffindor?” the old man suggested with a grin.

Now Molly and Arthur both began to look alarmed. Harry carefully moved his ankle out of Ron’s kicking range.

“So there’s to be no official investigation of how these men came to be here, and why they bloody near killed my little girl?” Mr. Granger asked tightly. Mrs. Granger was silent, but looked just as outraged.

Madam Bones sighed and sagged, just a little, in her chair. “I’m afraid it’s not that simple. I would like nothing better than to get to the bottom of how this occurred, but the High Mugwump is correct. There are… political factions… in the Wizengamot that would use what happened as leverage to pass more laws restricting Muggle-born wizards and limiting our access to the Muggle world. I also agree that such a political backlash is precisely why they were used and discarded in such a despicable fashion.”

Augusta Longbottom spoke up for the first time. “Madam Bones’ assessment of the political climate is accurate. If anyone can think of a way her office can get justice for those men without rolling back the last three decades of political progress, then they should speak up immediately.”

There was a long silence.

“At least,” Dumbledore ventured after a long, uncomfortable pause, “whoever set this in motion will no doubt be disappointed that their long term plans have failed.”

“And I will be stationing a team of Aurors in Hogsmeade to make sure nothing else like this is attempted,” Madam Bones added. “No one will protest the removal of the Dementors after what happened.”

And with that, the die was cast. Harry was a little surprised, at least at first, that he and his friends had been included. Later he discovered that Arthur, and to a lesser degree Molly, were responsible for that. The Weasley patriarch had reminded the headmaster that Harry should be part of the decision-making process… otherwise he was likely to follow his own path if he disagreed with their conclusions. Harry privately admitted that was probably true. He just wasn’t sure if they were being considerate, or he was becoming too predictable.

The following day, the drama began far too early for Harry’s tastes; specifically, when Ron refused to leave the dormitory for breakfast. Harry was half a mo’ from getting Madam Pomfrey when he realized his friend wasn’t sick.

This was no doubt a good thing. Any infirmity capable of putting Ron Weasley off his feed was undoubtedly life-threatening. He was reassured, but puzzled when Ron asked if he’d mind bringing him back something from the Great Hall.

“If you want to eat,” Harry asked, “then why don’t you come down with us? You’re not sore from the other day, are you?”

“Er, no,” Ron mumbled, looking down at his feet. “Just don’t want to see everyone staring at me. Bad enough when it’s just Gryffindor, but the whole school? Blimey…”

Harry blinked. This was unexpected. “What happened to wanting to stand out from your brothers?” he asked. “I don’t think a Weasley has ever done all that, yeah?”

Ron scowled. “I may have felt like that when I first came to Hogwarts,” he muttered, “but I’m not eleven years old anymore.”

Harry swallowed, trying to ignore a stab of guilt. “I’m not saying it’s a bad thing, you know, just looking for a silver lining and all that.”

“Besides,” Ron continued like he hadn’t heard a word, “I feel like a huge fraud.”

“What?” Harry demanded.

“If you hadn’t insisted we all learn the Patronus, they’d have overrun us from the start,” Ron continued doggedly. “And that bloody great stag of yours did the lion’s share of the work. But all anyone cares about is me stabbing one. One!”

Harry shook his head. “We all worked together to hold them back, Ron. But what you did… protecting Hermione… killing that thing. Killing it, Ron! No one’s ever done that before. I’ve never even heard of someone wounding one before.” He paused, looking Ron straight in the eye to emphasize the next word. “Ever.”

Ron’s eyebrows slowly went up. “Not… ever?”

“No. As in, ‘what the bloody hell is he doing?’ and ‘oh my lord!’”

“But you said… you told me to…”

“I was guessing at that point – I, uh, remembered something I’d heard once, like a legend.” Harry explained, mindful of his dorm mates stirring. “But you’re the one who put yourself in that position in the first place.” Harry let that sink in. “Do you want to know something else I heard?”

Ron shook his head.

“The sword of Gryffindor can only be wielded by a true Gryffindor, someone the sword itself considers worthy. The enchantments that let it kill a Dementor wouldn’t have worked for a fraud.”

“Really?” Ron asked in a small voice.

Harry sighed. “You can ask Dumbledore if you don’t believe me,” he added with a frown.

Ron shook his head quickly. “No, no I believe you Harry. It’s just… a lot to take in.”

Harry smiled. “You’d be a prat if it wasn’t. Now let’s get out of here before we make Neville and the others sick with all this sentiment.”

“Too late,” Seamus groused as he stuck his head out from under the covers.

Unfortunately, any hopes Harry nurtured for easing his friend back into normality – or what passed for it at Hogwarts anyway – were dashed by the heap of Owl Post that was dumped next to Ron’s plate.

His friend definitely began to look a bit green. Not a good complexion to have under that ginger thatch either. As he stared at the growing mound of envelopes, Hermione finally had enough.

“This is ridiculous,” she huffed. “Soon you won’t be able to see your plate.” With a flick of her wand the mailings were neatly stacked and organized. She waved her wand over them a bit more carefully and nodded. “None of them appear to be charmed,” she observed, “though I’d be surprised if anything like that could get through the wards. I read in Hogwarts: A History that the school has special owl wards to prevent charmed packages from being delivered – at least not if the charms are on the outside wrappings. Not that they are one hundred percent effective. There are special potions and elixirs you can soak wrapping paper in that prevent the detection of dangerous charms placed on the contents, but the charms still have to be fairly subtle for that to work…” She paused, catching her breath. She blushed faintly as she realized that everyone was looking at her with varying expressions. “Well, anyway, it should be safe to handle, at least.” Her blush grew more pronounced when she saw Ron’s extremely grateful expression.

“Er, would you mind helping me sort these out then?” Ron asked in a small voice. “I have no idea how to respond, but Mum would have my ears if she thought I was being rude and didn’t respond like I should.”

“Ron, are you sure?” Hermione asked in a small voice. “I don’t know as much as I should about Wizarding culture. I could miss something, or give bad advice. I could—”

Ron shook his head. “Just make sure I sound polite,” he said. “My family doesn’t put a lot of stock in the really swotty bits. I just don’t want to sound like a complete git.”

“Er, I can give you a run down of the basics,” Neville offered. “Gran can be a bit, er, formal, at times. She made me learn all the old forms. A lot of it seems a bit daft, but most people don’t go that far.”

Hermione seemed to relax a bit when she realized she’d at least have someone to ask questions of. “I’d be happy to help, Ron,” she said, her blush returning.

Peter continued to thrash for a moment after the Cruciatus curse was lifted. It wasn’t fair, he raged silently as he panted on the ground. His master’s sources within the Ministry had identified the best Muggles to use. Peter didn’t think the plan was a bad one. He’d heard Lily, years ago, lecturing James on the conflicts in the Muggle world. Tricking them into attacking Hogwarts would ignite a firestorm of rage in the Wizarding World.

Under his master’s orders, a few discreet Imperios allowed him to locate a leader among the Irish Muggles fighting the British government. With the man’s active assistance, they’d formulated a story that would get Sean and his other fighters to attack Hogwarts and damage the wards keeping the Dementors off of the grounds.

But that was when the whole thing fell apart. Instead of pictures of students who’d been Kissed, the papers were full of stories about the students driving them from the grounds. Even more, there were claims that an heir of Gryffindor had emerged during the battle. The youngest Weasley boy. That last detail drove his master into a rage that left Peter Pettigrew twitching on the fine carpet, desperately trying to maintain control of his bodily functions.

He’d done his part right. This wasn’t his fault!

Peter wondered if he might be safer serving another…

42

Goblet Problems

Harry let out a quiet sigh as he listened to Ron's snoring rising above the general din. He'd pretended to turn in early, but as soon as he pulled closed the curtains around his bed, he had the Marauder's Map out. Watching it with a very faint Lumos spell under the covers gave him some idea of what was going on.

By the time he activated the map, Throckmorton and Umbridge were in Dumbledore's office, along with the headmaster and Professor McGonagall. They didn't appear to be moving around very much, so they were probably seated. This went on for over an hour before Throckmorton and Umbridge's names moved to the edge of the office and disappeared from the map. They had obviously left using the headmaster's Floo connection. Harry watched McGonagall's name leave the office and make its way to the professors' quarters.

Harry ground his teeth when the deputy headmistress stopped briefly at the door to Remus Lupin's suite. Harry ignored her name as it then proceeded to her rooms. He instead followed Remus's name as it traced McGonagall's path back to the headmaster's office. It only stayed there a quarter of an hour before leaving.

Harry opened his curtains. The dormitory was dark, if not so quiet. The largesse of the Welcoming Feast was pretty effective at sedating teenage boys. He carefully slipped his shoes on and pulled on his Invisibility Cloak. Harry slipped out of the room without waking anyone. The common room itself was largely deserted; a few upper years were dozing over their textbooks. Harry guessed they were hoping to get a head start on their NEWT preparatory classes. No one noticed the Fat Lady's portrait slide aside for a moment.

Harry heard the shuffle of Remus' footsteps well before the man came into sight. And what a sorry sight it was. With no one to witness it, the genial professor was the picture of dejection. Harry swallowed as his worst fears were confirmed. He edged away as the man fumbled with his door. He paused once he was over the threshold, and Harry could imagine him surveying his modest rooms with a note of despair. He was able to slip in behind the man before he turned to close the door.

Remus sat down at his desk, opened a bottom drawer, and pulled out a bottle that Harry recognized as a Christmas present from Sirius: a decanter of Ogden's Finest. As he worked on the seal, Harry cleared his throat and flipped back the hood of his cloak.

Remus gave a violent start and nearly dropped the bottle. "Good heavens," he gasped, "what on earth are you doing here?"

"Well," Harry began, "I was up to no good this evening."

"Ah yes," he murmured, "the map. Well, no matter, I'm sure word would have reached you within a day anyway."

Harry shrugged. "A notorious bigot visits the headmaster, who suddenly sends for you. Not hard to guess."

"Yes, well, I don't know if they did background checks on everyone as part of the tournament, or if someone tipped them off. Either way, my condition is recorded at Saint Mungos from when I was bitten, and the Ministry doesn't want anything that could… besmirch Hogwarts' reputation."

"Load of old tosh," Harry snapped.

"Nevertheless, I find myself without a job now. I understand that Madam Umbridge will refrain from alerting the press as long as I leave quietly."

Harry ground his teeth. "And you're just going to let her run you out? Call her out!"

"Harry, my affliction is a matter of medical fact. Stating it is hardly grounds for a duel."

"What about patient confidentiality?" Harry asked, "Your healer—"

"Was merely obeying the law. Healer confidentiality is not quite like it is in the Muggle world," Remus explained, "and in any event the Ministry makes a specific exception for reporting lycanthropy."

"They're just using the laws to justify being filthy bigots," Harry snapped.

Remus peered at him. "Possibly. The headmaster thinks the gentleman from International Cooperation just wants to avoid any possible problems. Madam Umbridge, on the other hand, struck him as… quite zealous… in the pursuit of her duties. Why are you so worked up about this?"

"Because it's not fair!" Harry all but shouted.

"Harry, I knew this would happen if my secret ever got out. I'm almost surprised it took this long – I thought I might even break the curse on this position."

Harry took a deep breath and blew it out. "What are you going to do now?"

"Well, I suppose I need to look for work. I've got a bit saved up, so I should be fine for a while."

Harry shook his head. "You don't need to search," Harry said.

"Harry, I appreciate…"

"How's your Occlumency?" Harry asked.

Remus blinked. "Not that great," he admitted. "It appears that my condition may make it a little more difficult to master…"

"Well, now you have time to work on it," Harry said quickly. "Go see Padfoot, he might be able to help."

"Harry, I don't need charity, I can…"

"Padfoot needs walking," Harry cut in, "among other things. See if you can find a way to circumvent the wards around The Burrow, then plug the holes. Come up with exercises I can use for the Duelling Association. Look for a certain rat. You are too clever, too hard-working, and too devious to let your talents go to waste." Harry paused. Time to play dirty. "Remus, I need every advantage I can get if I want to live past graduation. Do you really want to tell me no?"

By the end, Remus was staring at Harry with his mouth hanging open. He slowly closed it. "What are you not telling me?" he finally asked.

Harry shook his head. "Nothing Padfoot can't tell you when the time is right. Can you trust me that long?"

Remus slowly nodded.

Harry let out a sigh of relief. "Good. Do you want some help packing?"

Harry was more than a little bleary the following morning. Between helping Remus and dashing off a quick note for Hedwig to take to The Burrow, it was quite late before he finally made it to bed. He was dragging all through breakfast, and nearly fell asleep harvesting Bubotuber puss in Herbology. By lunch time he had a dull, pounding headache behind his eyes that made it difficult to focus on Charms that afternoon. By the evening meal, he was focused on eating as quickly as possible and going to bed early.

He was in fact so fatigued that it took him a moment to realize that Professor Dumbledore had stood up to make an announcement. With his attention finally drawn to the Head Table, he also noticed a familiar grizzled head of hair amongst the faculty. Moody.

"Unfortunately, Professor Lupin has had to withdraw from Hogwarts for personal reasons," Dumbledore announced. Harry supposed that was technically true. "He will be sorely missed, but I am pleased to introduce our new Defence Against the Dark Arts teacher, Professor Moody."

The retired Auror rose to his feet, both eyes surveying the silent Great Hall.

"I'm sure you will all make him feel welcome as he assumes his new duties," Dumbledore continued, blithely ignoring the dubious looks coming from many of the students. The Slytherins in particular seemed distinctly uneasy. Harry didn't need to wonder why. He imagined in 'certain families' misbehaving children were warned that if they didn't mend their ways, Alastor Moody would get them. Harry smiled a little at that thought, and soon had Ginny elbowing him with a questioning look.

"It's nothing," he murmured. "I just think Defence is going to be… interesting… this year."

The week passed quickly, especially after Harry got caught up on his sleep again. He was especially looking forward to Defence, as he'd actually never had this class taught by the real Professor Moody before. Whatever expectations he may have had, an empty classroom wasn't one of them. None of the Gryffindors who'd had him earlier that week would talk about their first class, at Moody's request and backed up by the prefects. Harry was intrigued enough to play along, so he didn't make an effort to find out ahead of time. Hermione, he noted, was practically tied in knots: her desire to know and be prepared was warring with her distaste for breaking the rules. She 'compromised' by reading through the entire fourth year textbook before setting foot in the classroom. Harry didn't think it would help much, but he wasn't about to tell Hermione that.

Wanting to be ready for anything, Harry urged his friends to all take seats in the left front corner of the classroom. He had a feeling Moody would want to make an impression on people for the first lesson, and he already knew the man's favourite saying.

As they sat down, Harry palmed his wand and murmured "Homenum revelio" as he swirled it around. He smiled after twitching it toward the back corners of the room. "There's someone in the back left corner," he murmured.

Hermione looked like she just barely caught herself before she turned to look. "Disillusioned?" she whispered back.

Harry nodded. "Get ready to take cover," he advised. The remaining students filed in, looking around curiously until the bell rang for the start of class.

Harry barely caught the flash of light as the red jet of a stunning spell shot out of thin air towards his seat. He dived for the floor with Ron, Hermione, and Neville following a half-second behind. With a jab of his wand, Harry flipped the desks behind them into the air. Two more stunning spells hit the ancient wooden desks and dissipated. Hermione was raising an area shield while Ron and Neville sent their own stunning spells toward their unseen assailant.

The rest of the class dissolved in to a panicked mob as students scrambled for cover. Seamus had the bad luck to leap to his feet right into the path of one of the stunners, and hit the floor out cold. Lavender and Parvati let out shrieks as they cowered down in their seats.

Hermione's wide area shield held up for three hits before it went down, leaving her panting. Harry sprayed the back corner with a slightly over-powered Aguamenti, and for an instant saw a figure outlined in the flying water. Ron and Neville saw Harry's spell and instantly switched from stunners to freezing charms. The overlapping charms left a rime of frost on the floor as the conjured water froze. Bits of ice fell from where they had frozen in mid-air. Harry used this to aim a Wind Charm that sent loose papers and quills flying toward the back of the class.

It also triggered a loud thump and a muttered curse from the back of the room.

Harry was starting to smile when he felt a tingle and his robes suddenly became extremely heavy and confining. He toppled over onto his side before he realized his outer robes had been transfigured into stone. He tried to change them back as a stunning spell made an awkward wobbling arc that brought it over Hermione's recast shield and down onto her shoulder. She fell and Ron, distracted, joined her a second later.

Neville was almost hit, but he got his shield up in time. But their unseen assailant didn't give him a moment's respite, and stunning spells kept up a constant pounding as Longbottom gritted his teeth and reinforced his shield charm. Harry felt his robes soften and shift back as Neville fell to his knees. Harry debated whether it was wise, but finally decided he couldn't take any chances. He gathered his strength as he raised his wand, a blasting charm on his lips—

"Alright, that's enough," a voice rasped from the back of the nearly empty classroom. The rain of stunners stopped and Neville took a deep, gasping breath. Harry made an effort to relax, forcing his magic back down as he felt sparks of static snap from his hair and fingertips.

Harry sat up, wand in his hand, still facing the back of the room as Neville revived Ron and Hermione. There was a shimmer and Mad-Eye Moody appeared, damp but grinning like a madman. Students began to shuffle back into the room, and out in the hallway Harry could see some seventh year prefects, along with several suits of armour.

Professor Moody revived the other students as Harry and his friends took their seats again. The upended desks were righted with a few flicks of Moody's wand.

By the time everyone was settled, Moody was back in front of the class, his robes dried and his eye spinning wildly. "Can anyone guess the purpose of this exercise?" he asked.

Hermione's hand was up first. At Moody's nod she spoke: "Always be aware of your surroundings?"

He nodded. "Yes, and always be ready for what could happen. I always told my trainees the most important thing about being an Auror. Do you know what that was?"

Hermione shook her head. Moody had everyone's attention now; Harry was really tempted to answer, but it would raise too many questions.

"CONSTANT VIGILANCE!" the grizzled old Auror thundered, making everyone jump. Harry couldn't help but smile.

The class went well after such a dramatic beginning. Harry enjoyed it, even though he was dreading the end of it.

Sure enough, Moody asked him to stay behind for half a mo.

"Yes, Professor?" Harry asked as the last of the fourth years filed out. He knew his friends would be waiting for him out in the hallway.

"Potter. care to explain what I saw here today?"

Harry nodded. "A lot of people have been taking shots at me since I returned to the Wizarding World," he said. "We've been training self-defence and tactics in our spare time. We're also getting tutoring during the summers as well."

"Your friends as well?" Moody asked, looking sceptical.

Harry shrugged. "They know if they hang around me, they are likely to be targets as well. I'm just chuffed they feel I'm worth it."

Moody nodded. "Fair enough. I understand you are also involved in the school's Duelling Association?" There was a noticeable hint of contempt at the end.

"Sort of. Professor McGonagall approves the curriculum. We're a little more focused on practical applications."

"So you say. Maybe I'll have to come have a look. In the meantime, take 20 points for you and your friends. That was the first time I didn't have a clean sweep, ever," he added sourly.

OoOoO

Harry played it straight and didn't warn Ginny or Luna before their first class with Moody, though he did say it was "interesting". He was questioned about this rather closely after the Friday class with the Gryffindor and Hufflepuff third years. From what Harry gathered, when Luna entered the classroom she simply walked up to the disillusioned Moody and said good morning. This lead to an uncomfortable meeting after class with Moody and McGonagall, until Harry cut to the chase and swore a magical oath that he had not revealed the ambush to Ginny or Luna.

At that point, Luna mentioned that professor McGonagall always started her first year classes disguised in her Animagus form, to give her new students a surprise. When she didn't see Professor Moody in the classroom, she wondered if he might be doing the same. She also pointed out that his disillusion charm didn't cover the aroma of the pickled herrings he'd had for breakfast.

Harry remained silent during her explanation. He didn't think he'd ever heard Luna Lovegood sound quite so irritated. From the wide-eyed expression on Ginny's face, Harry didn't think he was the only one, either.

In the end, the gruff retired Auror apologized to all of them and gave Luna twenty points for her observational skills. Then he started asking them about the Duelling Association and what they'd be practicing in there. By the end of the hour, Harry felt a little wrung out, but between him and Hermione they'd filled four feet of parchment with ideas for group exercises. Moody had also volunteered to co-sponsor the club. The gleam in the old man's eye made Harry worry a bit, but he couldn't really see a gracious way to demur.

OoOoO

Harry's first letter from Remus eased any concerns he had about his spur of the moment offer. He dutifully reported that Padfoot was responding well to the extra walking, and was trying to teach Remus himself a new trick or two. It was a bit of work, but he expected he'd pick it up soon enough. Some more ideas for the Duelling Association were included as well. He hadn't found anything he could exploit in the wards, but he didn't expect to so soon. Molly and Arthur were both fine and sent their love as well.

On a separate issue, a private barrister had been secured to look into the matter of the trial records of Sirius Black, or rather why there weren't any. The Ministry was dragging its feet, of course, but it was at least a start. One point in their favour: Bartemius Crouch, Senior, was looking at a long sentence in Azkaban for abetting a jailbreak, and his influence in the Ministry was a thing of the past. In fact, some parties that were previous stonewalling against any inquiry were now in favour – just as long as any blame would be laid on Crouch and not them.

That last development didn't exactly please Harry, but he would take what he could get. There were things going on that he didn't really understand, but he didn't really have anything he could do to change that. It was rather annoying, and he wondered privately how much it annoyed his friends in first and second year when they were in the same position. He wondered how they made it through without wanting to hex him. On second thought, he was sure they all did at some point.

At least they had plenty to keep themselves busy. Between Moony and Moody's contributions, the Duelling Association was breaking new ground. The retired Auror favoured group exercises that Harry was fairly certain were cribbed straight from Auror training courses. Professor McGonagall wondered aloud at the need for such things, only to have Moody sourly ask how likely it was for the students to be attacked by Dementors in Hogsmeade. Harry cut his eyes downward so he didn't have to see her face, but her clipped acceptance of the retired Auror's point still made him wince. He wondered if the old man had a death wish, or really was round the twist like everyone claimed.

Either way, Moody won the argument, and the Duelling Association exercises became much more complex. To be honest, Harry found them to be both challenging and fun. This was something he'd never really had a chance to study before, and he was hooked from the start. They did make him cringe occasionally as the lessons highlighted some of the mistakes made by his future self, but what could he expect if he'd been thrown into a war with little to no training? He tried to redirect these surges of chagrin and self-loathing with limited success.

All said, it was probably for the best that Professor Dumbledore didn't attend the Duelling Association meetings.

Harry could draw some comfort from the realization that at least now he knew better. And he doubted his future enemies were training like this.

At least he hoped they weren't.

"Hagrid, do you really think this is a good idea?" Harry asked.

"Got special permission to do this," the half-giant beamed happily, "as a special project for the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures." He coughed into a massive hand and then murmured under his breath. "Professor Dumbledore thought it would look right proper to have something new to show those other schools."

Harry blinked as he looked down at the (currently) tiny Blast-Ended Skrewts. "Well, they certainly are different." While he supposed it made some kind of mad sense to try and show off for the visiting schools, it also meant he had absolutely zero chance of talking Hagrid out of cultivating the ruddy menaces. He glanced over at Hermione who had a rather sickly grin on her face as Hagrid rambled on about his newest "misunderstood, but really interesting creatures". She shook her head slightly, so Harry guessed she didn't have any ideas either.

Bugger.

Finally October drew to a close and the day came for the Beauxbatons and Durmstrang contingents to arrive. Harry was growing increasingly nervous. Although he'd been interrupted during the welcoming feast, Professor Dumbledore didn't make any further announcements regarding the Tri-Wizard Tournament.

A couple of days after seeing to Remus Harry heard Fred and George plotting to enter the tournament and stopped short. There had been no mention made of age restrictions for the champions. He almost wanted to ask to see if they had just forgotten to mention them, but that could be a little awkward to explain… especially if they had been discussed, but discarded. The last thing Harry needed was accusations of using listening charms.

It was inconceivable that Professor Dumbledore would have let the lower years plot and plan for this long if he was still planning to institute an age line like Harry remembered. So it seemed likely there would be no age restrictions, as in previous tournaments. The champions would most likely still be seventh years, assuming the goblet chose based on magical knowledge, power, skill, or some reasonable combination of those.

But that just begged the question. Why was this different? And if this was different, what other changes could Harry expect? And were these minor deviations, or a sign that everything was starting to go off the rails? All these questions and uncertainty were making Harry acutely uncomfortable as he and his friends lined up to await the arrival of the students from Beauxbatons and Durmstrang.

As before, the French contingent arrived first, their flying carriage drawing shouts of awe from the students lined up in front of the castle. Harry smiled, admiring the huge winged horses, each the size of an elephant. No less impressive was the second person to exit the carriage (after the carriage boy in blue robes that unfolded the steps), Madam Maxime was easily as large as Hagrid, but was dressed to the nines in a smart outfit of black satin and opals that made Dumbledore look almost provincial in comparison.

But as the students followed their Headmistress out of the carriage, there seemed to be more than the dozen or so that Harry remembered from before. He didn't doubt that the inside of the carriage was larger than the outside – no more than a handful would have fit alongside Madam Maxime otherwise. Rather than just the oldest, there was a smattering of younger students as well. If there was any question remaining about the age restriction, that removed it. It wasn't hard to pick out Fleur in the crowd; he still remembered consoling her after the news about Bill. His older self was one of the few men in the Order of the Phoenix that could get near her when her emotions were running riot. It probably helped that he himself was so dead inside.

Harry shook himself a little as he pulled his mind back to the present. Some of the other students looked familiar, but that was probably just lingering recognition from their 'first' visit. Harry felt the tension rise in his neck and shoulders as he gazed in the general direction of the lake. The next arrivals would be noticeably less pleasant to deal with.

He sucked in a breath as a disturbance formed in the glossy black surface of the lake. The bubbles gave way to a whirlpool with a squelching sound. Soon a mast appeared as the Durmstrang ghost ship rose from the deep. Harry looked over at Hermione and grimaced. She knew enough details from their talks to know something was wrong, and by the way she was worrying at her lower lip, Harry knew she was also trying to figure out the reason for the changes.

Harry already knew from the Daily Prophet about Snape's ascension to headmaster, but it still sent chills down his spine to see the sallow-faced man standing on deck in a sable-furred cloak. His black eyes glittered as he led his students off the deck, their own, shaggier cloaks making them seem to loom larger than life.

"Oh bloody effing hell!" Ron suddenly snarled, his voice quiet, but angry enough to make the students around him flinch. McGonagall sent a quick look in their direction, but Harry didn't think his friend even noticed.

"Ron," Hermione whispered, "we knew Professor Snape would be back. Why are you-?"

"It's not him," Ron snapped, "look behind the git."

"Oh hell," Harry groaned quietly. McGonagall looked like she was about to go for her wand, but that was the least of his worries at the moment. The figure immediately behind Snape coming down the gangplank sported hair of a rather distinctive shade of pale blond. One that Harry would rather not encounter again. Draco Malfoy had found a way to return to Hogwarts.

As the Hogwarts students followed their new guests into the castle, McGonagall approached them looking less than pleased. Ron, however, was having nothing of it. No sooner had she pulled them into an antechamber before he spoke up.

"Professor," the redhead asked with noticeable heat, "what is Draco doing here?"

McGonagall seemed a little off-balance that Ron was opening the discussion. "He is a Durmstrang student, and thus eligible to attend." She paused. "I also enquired as to the… suitability… of his presence. I was informed that tournament by-laws do not permit any student be denied access to the hosting school, upon penalty of forfeiture. I understand that was codified to prevent the hosting school from exercising an unfair advantage by barring the visitor's best possible contestants."

"Draco, a Tri-Wizard champion?" Ron scoffed.

"As improbable as it might seem," the stern professor allowed, "we cannot bar him from the wards until after the Goblet has made its choice."

Ron looked a little mollified. Harry still had a bad feeling about this. Malfoys never played by the rules. While he hadn't seen Draco in well over a year, the boy he saw trailing Snape didn't seem like the arrogant git he remembered. He was a lot quieter, for one thing, not speaking once that Harry could see, merely glancing impassively about.

"We understand that Professor Dumbledore might not have had a choice," Hermione began in a conciliatory tone, "but it would have perhaps been nice to warn Draco's, er, victims beforehand. I understand that in a Muggle school they would have been given advance warning and perhaps been allowed to skip functions where they would meet."

"I don't need to run from him," Ginny added, a little irritably.

"I know," Hermione agreed, "but it would have been nice to give you a choice. Or some advance notice."

McGonagall sighed. "We did not receive the final lists until last night. Had I more time, I would have been happy to provide such notice," she said in a clipped tone.

"I see," Hermione replied. She turned to Ron. "This is clearly just an unfortunate situation. Surely you can see that?" she asked, clearly trying to play the peacemaker before Ron said something to alienate their head of house.

Ron reluctantly nodded.

"We will be keeping an eye out to make sure everyone is on their best behaviour, Mister Weasley," Professor McGonagall added, "and that includes Draco Malfoy when he is on school property."

"I'm sure Professor Moody is looking forward to that," Harry added with a smile. He was pretty sure he didn't imagine the alarmed look that flashed across McGonagall's face for a split-second, displacing her normally stern expression.

"Professor Moody will likely have other responsibilities guarding the Goblet of Fire," she declared.

Luna looked up from where she was writing on a scrap of parchment. "Has it been officially declared that Draco will leave if he is not selected?" she asked in an innocent tone, "I'd like to make sure I get it correct. Daddy will be very interested."

Harry sighed. "She's right," he agreed. "There's no way the press won't pick up on this. Expelled former Hogwarts student returns for Tri-Wizard Tournament. It's too juicy a story to ignore, and I'm sure he'll be more than happy to tell his version of events."

Ron shuddered. "Wait till my Mum hears about this!"

Their conversation with Professor McGonagall, unsatisfying as it was, at least ended quickly enough for Harry and his friends to be seated in the Great Hall with no fuss. Unsurprisingly, he saw the Durmstrang students sitting at the enlarged Slytherin table. They were clustered near the end closest to the High Table. Throughout its length Draco was being treated like a returning hero, a sight that re-ignited the spark of anger burning in the pit of Harry's stomach.

The Beauxbatons students, however, rather than sitting at the Ravenclaw table as Harry remembered, were gathered at one end of the Gryffindor table. It was the end furthest from the High Table, and he wondered if it was a coincidence that it put them as far as possible from the Slytherin and Durmstrang students. Traffic was slowed for the Gryffindors, and Harry subtly steered his group clear of those who'd been slowed or outright dazed by the sight of Fleur Delacour. Harry smiled a little when he noticed Ron and Neville were largely unaffected by the half-Veela's charms. He wondered if it was Occlumency or something else.

Once they were seated, Harry glanced back down the table. The Beauxbatons students were all sitting in a cluster, making Harry wonder again if they were purposefully avoiding the Slytherins or the Durmstrang students. He frowned. There was a tall girl sitting next to Fleur that bothered him for some reason. She seemed younger, but was just as tall as the willowy platinum blonde, built noticeably sturdier with dark hair drawn into an elegant chignon. She was mostly solemn, but when she smiled once in response to something Fleur said, there was a sarcastic tilt to her mouth that seemed all too familiar.

Ginny's nudge made Harry aware he was staring. He looked down and then shook his head. "Does something seem odd about the girl sitting second from the end?" he whispered.

"I think the one on the end is the weird one," she replied tartly, "are you sure it isn't her you are staring at?"

Harry scowled. "No, I'm talking about the brunette sitting next to your future sister-in-law," he whispered.

Ginny's gobsmacked expression was a little satisfying, but Harry also wanted to reassure her he wasn't interested in Fleur. Getting to do both at once was just a happy efficiency.

Ginny snorted after a moment then glanced back up the table. "She's tall, but I think she's closer to our age than the blonde."

Harry pondered this a moment, then turned and stared. "Millicent?" he whispered.

Ginny blinked. "She's been through some changes then."

Harry nodded, and then looked away. Fleur was glancing around again, and he didn't want to be caught staring. Up at the High Table, he could see Cuthbert Throckmorton and Ludovic Bagman sitting with the professors and the heads of the other schools. While he supposed that Dolores Umbridge was the driving force behind forcing Remus out, the role Throckmorton played did not leave Harry well-disposed toward the man. Ludo was still the affable idiot that Harry remembered from the Quidditch World Cup, albeit a popular one.

The meal continued and Harry ate pretty much on autopilot as his mind churned. Snape was fairly impassive, his facial expression unchanging as he glanced around the room, including his former students. Professor Slughorn was seated next to him, clearly trying to start a conversation with little success. Harry wondered if that arrangement made Snape uncomfortable, being next to his replacement. Of course, Harry remembered, Slughorn had been the man to introduce Snape to potions, and been his former head of house. Maybe Dumbledore put him there so they could talk about brewing? Either way, Snape was having none of it.

With a silent Snape to his left, Dumbledore had a far more convivial dinner companion on his right. Madame Maxime seemed to be enjoying the change of scenery and a conversation with both Dumbledore and McGonagall. Here, the Triwizard Tournament seemed to live up to its promise of fostering greater international cooperation. Harry frowned when he couldn't recall what the seating arrangements had originally been, then decided he was likely overanalysing the whole thing.

It did make him smile to see Moody perched on the far right end of the table, as geometrically far from Snape as it was possible for him to be seated. Probably not by accident.

Finally, as the dinner concluded, Dumbledore stood and introduced the guests at the High Table. Sure enough, the celebrated former beater for the Wimbourne Wasps garnered far more applause than Throckmorton. This seemed to annoy the goateed man to no end. Got to love Quidditch fans, Harry thought. But after dumping Percy like that, he really deserved no better. Harry felt his mouth quirk. It still seemed a little unreal to feel so defensive about the occasionally prickly Weasley, but he'd really come around from Harry's memories of before. He had a good feeling after he got the news about the offer from Madam Bones – he thought working for her could be the best thing that could happen for Percy. Harry just hoped he could stop things from getting to the point where she is targeted again.

Harry shook his head when he realized he was wool-gathering while Dumbledore had Filch unveil the Goblet of Fire. The headmaster then began explaining the judging of the tournament tasks. He forced himself to listen closely and see if anything had changed. It all seemed as he remembered up until the end. The omission of the age line he expected, but for some reason the applicant slips from Durmstrang and Beauxbatons were being dropped into the Goblet of Fire by Snape and Maxime, respectively, who had evidently collected them ahead of time. It seemed like a minor change, but it left Harry wondering what had caused it. The Hogwarts students still had twenty-four hours to submit their names. Perhaps one of the other headmasters had suggested this at the last minute. Still, it was curious.

It wasn't long before they were all dismissed for the night and the foreign students made their way back to their respective conveyances. Harry wondered if he'd get a chance to see how Millicent was doing as a Beauxbatons student. As they made their way back to Gryffindor Tower, Fred and George were talking about setting up a betting pool on who the goblet would select for each school and how they would fare in the tournament. As they were entering the common room, Fred asked him if he was thinking about putting his name in the cup.

Harry frowned. "I'm not sure a fourth year would know enough to compete with seventh year students. At least, not without making a fool of myself."

"I don't know," George replied, "I think you'd make a pretty good show of it myself."

"All things considered," Fred added with a sly grin, "I think we'd get pretty good odds on you, too."

Harry rolled his eyes at the twins. Businessmen to the end. Trust them to leverage knowledge of a possible future apocalypse to beat the bookmaker's odds. "I rather think I'd prefer to have a nice quiet year myself," he shot back. No use making it easy for someone trying to resurrect Voldemort, after all.

"I think you're selling yourself short there," George argued before letting the matter drop.

But this conversation sparked an even bigger discussion in the common room regarding who would try out and who they thought might from the other houses. Harry stayed quiet through this, but listened avidly as he went through some of his old transfiguration essays and notes. Part of it was curiosity, and part of it was a desire to keep an eye out for other potential changes. Hermione, who was sitting next to him organizing her charms notes, frowned at his inattention. Funny enough, Cedric Diggory's name did come up in the discussion of likely seventh years, but most of the room dismissed him as "the Pretty-boy Hufflepuff" to Harry's amusement.

Towards the end, Colin Creevey asked Harry what he thought.

"I don't know," Harry answered, "but I think Cedric might do all right."

Colin frowned. He started to say something, but was cut off when one of the prefects reminded everyone they needed to go to bed. Harry shrugged as he began picking up his papers. Hermione fussed at how disorganized he was.

Harry sighed. "It's not like I'm planning to bind each year's notes together and publish them as study guides, unlike some people I know…"

"And why not?" Hermione asked. "Maybe Ginny or Luna could use them? Or even your own children one day…"

Harry smiled at the implied optimism. "One, I know Ginny and Luna will be receiving a copy of your notes to use as a reference. Two…" He said as he picked up an essay for McGonagall's class and handed it to Colin, "Colin, can you read that?"

Colin peered at the paper and paused. Harry could see his lips move as he tried to decipher the cramped script. He looked up at Harry and gave a sickly grin. "Er, yes… I think."

Harry handed him another sheet of paper. "How about that?"

Colin peered at it. "Is this some sort of code?"

"Right," Harry said and turned back to Hermione. "My handwriting is complete rubbish. I have to work at it to make it legible for letters or things I have to hand in. When I'm taking notes, in a hurry… I doubt anyone else can decipher it."

Hermione just made a discontented sound as she gathered up her own papers and headed up to bed.

The following day was Saturday, and like half of Gryffindor, Harry and his friends decided to make an early go of things and headed down to the great hall rather than having a lie in. He was pleasantly surprised to see that the Beauxbatons students were also early risers, but the Durmstrang students were nowhere to be seen.

Everyone was eyeing the Goblet of Fire, burbling away atop the stool normally used for sorting new students. Harry could have sworn it should have been in the entrance hall, not the great hall, but otherwise nothing else seemed amiss.

Harry noticed none of the French students looked particularly anxious or excited. He paused near their end of the Gryffindor table. "Bonjour," he said, raising his voice slightly. When they looked up he continued. "Waiting to see who enters?" he asked.

The girls all glanced at Fleur, who seemed to be their unspoken leader. "Oui," she answered after a moment. "From 'ogwarts. Madame Maxime and ze headmaster from Durmstrang, have already placed ze names in ze goblet."

Harry frowned. He was still was curious about that change. "Ah, pardon me. I am Harry and these are my friends Hermione, Ron, Neville, Ginny, and Luna."

"We know," Fleur replied. She gave a half-smile toward the girl sitting next to her. "How do zey say? Ze reputation, it precedes you?"

Harry gave a theatrical sigh as he raised the back of his hand to his forehead. "Alas, I hope some of it was good?" he asked in a quavering voice.

That was good for a few giggles around the table. The brunette at Fleur's elbow rolled her eyes. "You know, I was just getting this lot to stop making fun of my accent," she replied sourly in distinctly not-French-accented English.

Hermione's eyes widened. "Millicent?" she gasped. "Is that you?"

"Yes, it's me," Millicent shot back, sounding a little defensive.

"Er, you look great, I mean, happier, too…" Hermione added, clearly trying to avoid giving offence.

"Maybe this isn't the best place to hold that conversation," Harry added quietly, looking around. He didn't see any unfriendly eyes, but there were a lot of people around, especially for a Saturday morning.

"We are planning to have a light luncheon at ze carriage," Fleur suggested, "Perhaps you could join us at noon?"

"That would be our pleasure," Harry agreed, the others nodding, before taking their own seats for breakfast.

Harry ate slowly as his friends talked in low voices. They all stopped to clap for Angelina Johnson when she entered her name. Everyone looked up when the outer doors banged open and the Durmstrang students marched in. Draco was still unnervingly quiet as they filed in. Again, Harry wondered what he'd been up to over the last year. A Malfoy with the self-control to keep his mouth shut was a dangerous curiosity.

Ron's eyes narrowed as he watched the procession of blood-red robes approach the Slytherin table. Then they widened. "Bloody hell," he gasped in a whisper, "look Harry, that bloke next to Draco, isn't that Victor Krum?"

Harry nodded. "You didn't see him last night?"

"No," Ron admitted. "I saw Draco and the rest was just a nasty blur."

"Maybe you'll get a chance to talk to him when he's away from the others?" Harry suggested.

Ron shook his head. "Not unless I can think of something better to say than 'Hey, I saw you at the World Cup!'. I mean, it made me really uncomfortable last term, after that whole 'Heir of Gryffindor' crap, when people I didn't know would just walk up to me and start blathering on about it. I wouldn't want to do that to someone else."

Harry blinked. "That's… pretty perceptive of you, Ron."

"Try not to act so surprised."

"In my defence," Harry shot back, "I have good reason to think you might."

"Good reason?" Ron asked, and then cringed. "Oh no, tell me I didn't… didn't, you know…"

"Gush?" Harry asked. "Like a broken water main."

Ron pushed back his plate and covered his face with his hands. "Oi, sometimes you are a terrible friend to have, Harry."

Harry just grinned and took a sip of pumpkin juice as Hermione patted Ron on the back and asked him what was wrong.

As Harry suspected, the Beauxbatons carriage was bigger on the inside than the outside. A lot bigger. The body of the carriage itself formed a vestibule with several doors that opened into corridors that stretched to who knows where. Fleur and Millicent were waiting for them, and led Harry and his friends to a small dining room, complete with a light brunch spread. Many of the other students were sitting scattered at various tables, chatting over pastries and small sandwiches.

"We find ze food at 'ogwarts, ah, heavy?" Fleur explained as they filled their plates.

"It's necessary to survive Scottish winters," Millicent replied. "I'd started to forget how cold it was here."

"You look like Beauxbatons climate agrees with you," Harry offered cautiously.

Millicent snorted in a rather unladylike fashion, making Fleur roll her eyes as the other girls tittered. "I'm just glad I missed the Dementor invasion," she shot back.

Most of the casual conversation in the room died at that point. Ron looked down and flushed when he noticed some of the French students eyeing him.

"It was not a lot of fun," Harry agreed quietly. "I am a little surprised you wanted to come back."

"I didn't, not initially anyway," Millicent agreed. "But my sponsor said I should be willing to face my past, or some nonsense like that."

"It iz not nonsense, mon ami," Fleur shot back. "You will show your enemies zat you are not afraid of them, zat you have allies now who will stand by you, and zere is nozzing zey can do about eet!" Harry noticed Fleur's accent got noticeably stronger when she was angry or maybe just passionate about something.

"Sponsor?" Hermione asked mildly. Ginny's grin showed she wholly agreed with Fleur's sentiment.

"It's a lot easier to do that now that my family is safely on the Continent," Millicent shot back at Fleur before turning to Hermione. "And while I may have had my tuition and expenses paid by my anonymous benefactors," Millicent explained, giving Harry a quick glance, "I still didn't know three words of French and I was starting over in a new school. Madame Maxime saw fit to assign me as a 'special project' to one of her prefects,"

"It was no hardship," Fleur said quietly. "I got a chance to practice my English, and as Madame Maxime said, ze added responsibility looked good on my application for Head Girl."

"You're the Head Girl at Beauxbatons this year?" Hermione asked, clearly impressed.

"She is," Millicent confirmed proudly. "But I don't think makeovers were included in what the Headmistress had in mind,"

"It ees difficult to do ones best, if you don't look your best," Fleur replied loftily. "A small change of diet, less of zat heavy English food, some cosmetic charms, and the services of a 'air-dresser and robe-maker zat actually want you to look good… zese are very small zings. But ze confidence, ze poise, zat is all you, mon ami."

"Yes, well…" Millicent said, flushing a little. Harry had to admit that her hair drawn back, emphasizing the strong lines of her face, was far more flattering that the hanging mess she almost seemed to be hiding behind at times.

"And zis Parkinson, she does not recognize you yet?" Fleur asked innocently. "She is ze one with ze tiny nose that turns up?"

"Yes, and I don't think she will unless someone points it out to her," Millicent answered sourly.

"Bon. 'opefully, when she does, you will get to see her, how do they say… eat her liver out? Yes?"

:Oui, Fleur," Millicent said, cracking a smile that seemed to transform her face. Harry noticed some of the Beauxbatons boys straightening a bit in their seats and had to suppress a smile of his own.

The meal was surprisingly pleasant. Fleur was much friendlier than Harry expected, and he suspected Millicent had a lot to do with that. Hinting at Harry's role in getting her transferred to Beauxbatons seemed to leave the French witch well-disposed toward Harry and his friends. As things progressed, the atmosphere relaxed even more and some of the students began asking about the so-called Battle of Hogwarts last term. At one point, Luna even pulled out her wand and demonstrated her corporeal Patronus that took the form of a duck-billed platypus, delighting many of the younger students.

Hermione and Fleur got into a detailed discussion of the differences between their two schools and how they approached the various subjects, with Hermione also interested in what being a head girl was really like. Harry had little doubt that was one of her goals for her own last year at Hogwarts.

Some of the Beauxbatons boys were curious about the whole mess with the Dementors and gradually drew Ron, Neville, and Ginny into a discussion of it, with Harry offering the odd bit. Ron was more than willing to discuss the small-unit tactics they used to initially repulse the incursion, but grew oddly reticent when it came to the climax of the battle.

Neville ended up doing most of the explaining regarding the Sword of Gryffindor, while Ron blushed from some of the awestruck looks he was receiving. One of the Beauxbatons fifth years, a lad named Sebastien, asked why he was being so modest.

"Not so much modest," Ron finally admitted, "as I don't remember what I was thinking at the time. I wasn't thinking, not really. I ran into the stupid thing because I couldn't think of anything else I could do, and I wasn't about to let it eat Hermione. I only reached into the hat to get Harry to stop shouting at me. After that it was just kind of automatic. I mean, if you had one of those things in your face I bet you'd want to stab it too."

"And taunting the rest of the horde?" Sebastien asked avidly.

"Er… too angry to think straight?" Ron offered weakly.

"Ah, but he saved Hermione from ze fiends," Sebastien's friend Amalthea added, "tres romantique!"

Ron, who had just started to drink from a goblet of some unnamed, but tasty juice concoction, broke down coughing. Neville resorted to thumping him solidly on the back to help clear the redhead's airways.

"We don't talk about that," Ginny explained. "Ever."

Harry and his friends lingered over some extremely good chicory coffee as the afternoon wore down. He was more of a tea drinker himself, but the dark aromatic liquid, served with milk and some sort of thick honey that broke down quickly under heat, was tasty enough to turn even his loyalties to tradition. Harry mused that they'd spent an afternoon fulfilling the avowed purpose behind reviving the whole tournament, and it hadn't even started yet.

Of course he was under no illusion that many of the people participating had other, less laudable motives. The ministry personnel seemed to be more focussed on maintaining the appearance of propriety and pushing their own agendas. Their treatment of Remus Lupin was a prime example of this. If he truly was a hazard to the students, the past year showed it was far less of one than that posed by the Ministry itself. And while the Beauxbatons students seemed friendly enough, there were no encouraging signs from their counterparts at Durmstrang. Harry feared that with Snape in charge, he wasn't likely to see any either.

Nonetheless, as they made their way back into the castle, it was fun to marvel at the elaborate Halloween decorations, and ask Fleur and her friends how Beauxbatons celebrated the holiday. It seemed that they didn't have anyone on staff that threw themselves into the decorating to the degree that professors Flitwick and Hagrid did… and Fleur seemed just fine with that after an animated Jack-O'-Lantern caught her off guard, eliciting a startled shriek.

Soon enough they were settled down in the lavishly-decorated Great Hall awaiting the Halloween feast. Harry wasn't particularly hungry yet, but the Great Hall seemed like more of a neutral ground than the Gryffindor common room. He wasn't even precisely sure if he needed to get permission from McGonagall to allow visitors, to be honest. He doubted she'd mind, but better to check first just in case. He certainly hadn't expected relations to be this warm after only a day. Of course, he had Millicent to thank for that.

The former Hogwarts student stayed by Fleur's side, solidifying Harry's impression that they were close friends. That wasn't something he'd ever anticipated, but it was probably all for the better. Knowledge of future events was a useful advantage, but he needed to remember that he was here to change things, and inevitably that meant his foreknowledge would eventually become less and less accurate. It was just hard sometimes, Harry admitted, to let go of a lingering sense of wrongness when things didn't follow his future memories. But it was something he was going to have to get used to if he was going to succeed here. It also didn't help his insecurities when he noticed some of those memories growing vague with respect to certain details. It was hard to discern whether that was due to the normal passage of time, or something else, and that made him even more nervous.

With an effort, Harry forced these speculations from his mind and rejoined the conversation as his friends settled at the Gryffindor table next to the Beauxbaton's students. Now was not the time to drive himself round the twist and he didn't want to give offense to their French guests by seeming aloof or preoccupied. Besides, they were discussing Quidditch and the dismal performances of both the French and English teams during the previous World Cup.

As Harry and Ron worked out the tentative details of arranging a pick-up game with Jean and Claude for the following weekend, Harry looked up at the additional students filing into the Great Hall and realized it was nearly time for the feast. He stretched a little, grimacing at how stiff he'd become sitting and talking the afternoon away. Harry excused himself to visit the necessary, but on the way back he ran into Hermione waiting for him in the corridor.

"You never mentioned being so friendly with the Beauxbatons students," she said in a quiet, but direct manner.

"That's because I wasn't," he admitted.

Her eyes widened. "You mean-?"

"Uncharted territory," Harry confirmed.

Hermione frowned and he noticed her teeth worrying at her lower lip. Sometimes Harry wondered if she was more dependent on his foreknowledge than he himself was. "But why?" she finally asked, "They seem perfectly nice to me."

Harry shrugged. This was hardly unexpected. Hermione was quite avid about picking apart the differences between the timelines and tracing back the causes. "Millicent is definitely a factor. They were…always… nice enough, I suppose. I got to know Fleur better later on. But initially, maybe a little standoffish." He grinned. "It didn't help that upon first meeting me, someone dismissed me as a 'little boy'."

Hermione's face purpled as she struggled to stop the giggles that erupted. "I can't see anyone doing that," she finally said with a commendably straight face.

"Of course," Harry agreed in as dry a tone possible.

Hermione sighed. "I meant that, you prat. You can be rather… well, intimidating to people that don't know you better."

Harry blinked. "What do you mean?" he didn't think he was acting that different, but how could he tell?

"Well," Hermione temporized, "you can be very direct, even with authority figures, if you think you know better. That's not a bad thing, per se, but I almost had a heart attack when you lit into my father when he was talking about taking me out of Hogwarts."

"It would have been a disaster, for you and for them," Harry protested.

"I agree," Hermione replied calmly, "but you were rather, ah, forceful when you were making your point. Father later said he hadn't had a wigging like that since he left the Royal Marines."

Harry blushed. He hadn't realized it at the time, but he'd probably gone overboard when he panicked.

"Don't apologize, Harry," Hermione added like she was reading his thoughts. "It was probably the only thing that stopped him. My father can be rather… well… emotional if he thinks me or Mum are in danger. Before we found out I was a witch, he nearly went spare trying to figure out if there was something, well, wrong with me when I started doing accidental magic." She smiled. "You and Ron and the others sticking up for me, well, you know I haven't really had a lot of friends in my life before Hogwarts. My parents were always rather concerned about that, so it really made an impression on them."

Harry swallowed and gave a rather sickly smile. "Well, I guess that's all right then."

Hermione nodded. "I'm not trying to make you self-conscious, Harry. If you are different than you remember being, that's only natural, and all to the good, I think. And you can be quite intimidating when you are angry. Of course that only makes sense."

Harry frowned. "How so?"

"It's common among powerful witches and wizards," Hermione replied. "When they are emotionally agitated, their magic reacts, and others can feel it. I've read about the effect, in extreme cases what they describe sounds similar to a strong electrical charge in the air. Anyone sensitive to magic can feel it, even if they don't know what's causing it."

Harry recalled the feeling in the air when Remus tried to test him against the Boggart. That was a bit more than Hermione described, but his unusual corpus magi could account for it. "Wait a minute, what about Professor Dumbledore? I don't think I've ever noticed that around him." Of course, in some of the more extreme situations in his future memories, he doubted he could have noticed a subtle anything.

"I thought about that as well," Hermione admitted, "I think that he has spent a great deal of time and effort making sure his emotions aren't easily agitated. With enough self-control, the book says, one can stop this process before it starts."

Harry supposed this was possible. The occasions where he himself had been calm enough to notice were ones where the Headmaster probably wanted to keep himself firmly under control. Other times, like the aborted duel with Voldemort in the Ministry of Magic, the magic was so thick in the air you could cut it with a knife. He doubted all of that was just coming from Voldemort. "That makes sense," he conceded.

"And it can be useful," Hermione added. "While no one is likely to underestimate you, it might also discourage others from, ah, opposing you, in the future."

That brought Harry up short. "That's… an interesting idea," he finally said. "I'm going to have to think that one over. In the meantime, we should probably get back to the Great Hall."

Hermione nodded and they left to join their friends.

Harry was glad they'd had a light lunch as they partook of the second Hogwarts feast in two days. He noticed the Durmstrang students were also sitting where they had the previous night. Tonight though, they seemed even friendlier with the Slytherins. Harry glanced up at the head table, but if Professor Slughorn had any feelings about this development, he wasn't making them obvious.

Conversation also seemed muted from the previous night, perhaps in anticipation of the drawing of the names. The Goblet of Fire had been moved, and was now sitting at the head table, simmering in front of Professor Dumbledore's place. Harry considered the innocuous-looking artefact as he lingered over his treacle tart.

Without Harry or Barty Crouch, Junior mucking things up, it would be a three-way race between Cedric Diggory, Fleur, and Victor Krum. Fleur hadn't fared that well, as Harry recalled, and he didn't see how her being friends with Millicent would change that. That meant it was likely down to Diggory or Krum, and Harry didn't think he was being overly sentimental when he favoured Cedric for the win. While it was true that Victor had been interfered with on the third task, Diggory was still more likely to beat him to the cup. Of course, whether that bit of history would repeat itself was anyone's guess.

Finally, the plates were cleared and Dumbledore rose to his feet.

"Well," the aged headmaster announced, "I see the goblet is almost ready to make its decision. I estimate it will require one more minute. When the champion's names are called, I'd like them to please come up to the top of the Hall, walk along the staff table, and go through that door into the next chamber, where they will receive their first instructions."

With that, Dumbledore gave a sweep of his wand that extinguished most of the candles in the room. With Hagrid's pumpkins providing the sole illumination in the cavernous Great Hall, the blue-white flames dancing above the lip of the Goblet shown as bright as day. In a moment, the audience in the dimly-lit hall gasped as a long tongue of red flame erupted from the Goblet of Fire. A charred scrap of parchment fluttered from it into Dumbledore's outstretched fingers.

"The champion," he announced, "for Durmstrang is Draco Malfoy."

A storm of applause and cheering erupted in the hall, much of it coming from the Slytherin table. Harry found that fortunate, because it drowned out the anguished "Bloody Hell!" that erupted from Ron's lips. Hermione twitched next to the horrified redhead, but to Harry's surprise didn't remark on his language. There was a scattering of polite applause from the Hufflepuff and Ravenclaw tables. The Beauxbatons students started to applaud, but it trailed off into a confused silence when they noticed the Gryffindors sitting mostly silent and stony-faced next to them.

Harry was still trying to figure out why the goblet would pick Draco Malfoy over Victor Krum. As he watched the blond silently stalk up the aisle and the leave the room, Harry felt a frisson of unease. There was no strutting or smiling for the new champion. Draco was utterly expressionless as he made his way out of the room. Something was wrong here…

As the noise died down, the goblet turned red again and a second slip of paper emerged.

"The champion," Dumbledore announced, "for Beauxbatons is Fleur Delacour."

This time, the applause and cheering was much more widespread. Harry clapped hard, and the whole Gryffindor table erupted with cheers. Fleur rose with a smile and the applause grew louder. Harry noticed the other Beauxbatons students didn't seem as upset as he remembered. He wondered if this Fleur was on better terms with her classmates or if it was something else. At least in this case, the Goblet of Fire seemed to be working normally.

Finally, the goblet turned red a third time. Harry found his eyes drawn to the Hufflepuff table as Dumbledore retrieved the third slip.

"The champion for Hogwarts is Harry Potter."

Harry's head snapped around to stare at the headmaster. As applause erupted around him, he couldn't help but echo Ron's earlier epithet.

"Bloody buggering hell."

43

A Stunning Victory

Harry rose to his feet, albeit a bit unsteadily. He'd halfway expected this, true, but it didn't make it any less annoying. Especially all the eyes resting on him. Most of them surprised, some envious, some contemptuous. He needed to get out in front of this, right now.

"Headmaster! What are you playing at?" Harry shouted, trying to sound as outraged as possible. Out of the corner of his eye, he saw Hermione jump a little.

Dumbledore blinked. "Mr. Potter, you need to follow me to…"

"How did my name come out of the Goblet when I didn't enter it?" Harry demanded.

"Liar!" someone in the crowd shouted. Harry didn't need to guess that it came from the Slytherin table.

Harry snatched the wand from its holster in a blur of motion and raised it. "I did not enter myself in this ridiculous tournament, nor do I know who did. I swear this on my life, my magic and my dead mother's soul!" He slashed the wand downward and the plate in front of where he'd been sitting split with a loud crack.

The Great Hall fell utterly silent. Ginny's eyes were wide and shining.

"Mr. Potter," the headmaster finally spoke. "Your name came out of the Goblet. You must come with me now."

"And if I refuse?" Harry asked.

"When your name came out, you were subject to a binding magical contract," Dumbledore replied carefully. "Breaking it would incur… harsh penalties."

"What if I destroy the Goblet first?" Harry asked, raising his wand again.

Dumbledore's eyes widened and for once, Harry saw the man lose his equilibrium. "Harry! No! I mean…" He swallowed as a flick of his wand raised an almost opaque shield around the quiescent Goblet. "Destroying an ancient, one of a kind artefact to avoid competing would not be seen kindly by the wizarding world, Mr. Potter."

"That's not my problem, Headmaster." Harry said flatly. He heard a few gasps. Dammit. People were not supposed to openly defy the Great Albus Dumbledore, Harry reminded himself. He needed to dial it back a notch before he revealed too much. Hermione was going to kill him stone dead. At least much of this could be attributed to his temper, which was well established in the Hogwarts Rumor Mill™.

"Your magic is held in abeyance by the Goblet, Mr. Potter. The destruction of the Goblet would likely invoke the penalties you seek to avoid."

Harry felt his shoulders sag a little as he lowered his wand. He was well and truly trapped. "Fine. I'll comply, as long as you answer one question."

"A question, Mr. Potter?" Dumbledore asked as he warily stepped toward Harry.

"What safeguards were in place to prevent someone from having their name entered by someone else against their will?"

The headmaster frowned. "But to be chosen means the Goblet selected you as the most capable contestant. It didn't seem… possible… that such a student wouldn't want to compete," he explained in a puzzled tone.

"Being good enough to be selected didn't keep contestants from dying in previous tournaments. Headmaster, my parents died to keep me safe. It is blasphemous to risk the life they sacrificed themselves to protect for a thousand galleons and eternal fame," Harry replied scornfully. The "you doddering old pillock" at the end went unsaid.

Dumbledore blanched. He turned and silently led Harry from the Great Hall, following the other champions.

Harry still felt many eyes on him as he left the hall, but overall the mood seemed more speculative than hostile. He would settle for that.

Shortly thereafter Harry found himself in the antechamber with Fleur and Malfoy. The French girl's eyes widened when she recognized Harry. "I thought you deed not want to enter ze tournament?" she asked softly.

"I didn't," Harry replied wearily. "The geniuses in charge of this never took any precautions to keep people from maliciously entering someone else."

"Spare us your dramatics, Potter," Severus Snape sneered as he moved beside Draco.

"Headmaster, did you hear the oath I swore?" Harry spat.

"The lad has a point," Moody growled, "Someone might be hoping Potter dies in this." Harry flinched a little at this. Too close.

"I look forward to competing, Headmaster," Draco spoke. "Testing myself against Hogwarts so-called elite should prove amusing."

Harry clamped down on his emotions with all his will. Even the sound of Draco's voice could make his magic surge now. Must not think of Ginny! he reminded himself. "I suppose embarrassing you again would be a silver lining," Harry agreed mildly.

Draco bristled, but was interrupted when Bagman spoke up. "Right, we need to give our champions their instructions. Cuthbert? Do you want to do the honors?"

Throckmorton stepped forward, consulting a folded piece of parchment. Harry was quietly relieved that he was still able to get a rise out of Draco. His new public demeanor was somewhat unnerving. A little self-control could make the prat actually dangerous.

"The first test," the Ministry official began, "is a test of your courage in the face of the unknown. As such, we will not be informing you of the particulars of the task until it begins on November 24th. You are not allowed to request, nor accept any assistance from your teachers for the tournament tasks. You will enter the first task armed only with your wand. You will receive details regarding the second task when the first one is over. Also, given the time demands of the tournament, champions are excluded from year-end exams, barring OWLS and NEWTS or the equivalents thereof." He turned to Dumbledore. "I think that covers everything, headmaster?"

Dumbledore nodded, but looked a little distracted to Harry.

Madame Maxime lead Fleur from the room as the meeting broke up. Harry hoped she and the Beauxbatons students could stay friendly even if they were competing now. He found his friends loitering in the hallway and his frown lessened a bit.

"Let's get out of here before Snape decides to have a go at us for old time's sake," Harry murmured. They agreed and quickly made their way back to the Gryffindor tower.

The noise from within the common room was faintly audible before they even gave the Fat Lady the password. When the portrait swung open, the sounds of celebration washed over them, making Harry scowl.

The cheers grew even louder as they entered and were spotted. The twins and Lee Jordan were stringing up a Gryffindor banner between the staircases. Angelina Johnson and the other chasers were passing out butterbeers someone had smuggled in from who knows where. Everyone was celebrating like Gryffindor had just won the Quidditch Cup.

Out of the corner of his eye, Harry saw Ron's face reddening. He felt a hollow feeling in the pit of his stomach.

The redhead opened his mouth, but his words were lost in the furore. His features twisted in anger as his face turned a shade of purple that would have done Uncle Vernon proud. A homemade banner touting Harry as the Gryffindor Triwizard Champion suddenly disappeared with a loud bang.

The common room fell silent as drifting ashes settled to the floor. Harry's own eyes widened. He couldn't remember the last time Ron had manifested accidental magic. His friend must have been beyond enraged.

"What the effing hell is wrong with you lot?" Ron roared. "Did you not hear Harry swear on his magic and his dead mum's soul that he didn't enter himself? Not an hour later we find you idiots celebrating someone having another go at him?"

"Why would someone enter him?" mocked a voice in the crowd. It was probably a good thing Harry couldn't see who it was from where he was standing. It sounded like that idiot McClaggen.

"Did anyone not hear a word I said this past week?" Hermione all but shrieked. "They stopped holding the Triwizard Tournament because of the death toll." She took a breath and steadied herself. "And before someone brings up eternal glory, I'll remind you that no one could name a single winner without visiting the library."

"Don't bother, Hermione," Ginny added. "Let's just head up. The Common Room seems to reek of stupidity tonight." She patted Harry on the shoulder and left for the girl's staircase. Hermione sniffed and followed, with Luna trailing behind.

Harry spared the room a single glance. Fred and George were both reddening, while Colin Creevey looked like he was about to cry. He shook his head and headed up the stairs to the fourth year boys room. Neville followed, chivvying Ron along.

The three of them were quiet as they prepared for bed. Harry didn't think it was a coincidence that Seamus and Dean seemed inclined to stay out late tonight.

Thankfully, the next day was a Sunday, so they had a chance to regroup before classes resumed. After an early breakfast in the Great Hall, Harry led his friends on a circuitous course to reach the Room of Requirement. The Marauder's Map ensured no one saw them.

The room gave them a table surrounded by comfortable-looking chairs. No sooner had they settled in than Hermione spoke up. "I think we need to get together and decide how we are going to approach this year."

"I assume you have some ideas, Hermione?" Harry asked in a slightly teasing tone.

Hermione's cheeks pinked up a little. "I think with what happened with the Dementors, it's safe to say that your foreknowledge is becoming compromised. The necessary changes you've made have had further and further reaching effects."

Harry nodded, conceding the point. "So if we aren't to keep our heads down, what do we do?"

"We still know some things that will happen, don't we?" Neville asked. "There are things that wouldn't have changed, right?"

"Voldemort is still out there," Harry agreed, "and he's still looking to return."

"I think we've addressed a lot of things," Hermione said thoughtfully. "Maybe we should work on contingencies. Voldemort might still find a way to return. One we don't know about."

"You mean neutralizing his power base," Harry said. "Death Eaters killed far more people than he did personally."

"We can't go around killing people!" Hermione gasped.

"We don't have to kill them to neutralize them," Ron said. "Harry, were the Bulstrodes friendly, you know, before?"

Harry shook his head.

"See, Hermione? Neutralized," Ron added. "You know, Harry, you can be a right scary bastard when you try to be."

Ginny chuckled and eyed Harry speculatively. "That's not the term some of the witches use," she purred, making Harry's ears burn.

"Ginny!" Ron hissed, causing her to break down in giggles.

"Most of the Death Eaters were male," Harry quickly pointed out, "but Ron might be onto something. A lot of people joined Voldemort after he returned. Coming back from the dead is apparently good for recruiting. If we can prevent a lot of that…"

"Building up an intimidating reputation can also backfire," Hermione warned. "At best, you'll be placing a large target on your back."

"He already has one because of that prophecy," Luna pointed out. "Voldemort already wants him dead."

"I think we have more to gain than lose, all told," Neville added.

"We?" Harry asked, raising an eyebrow.

"We're going to be watching your back, so we'll be dealing with a lot of the threats," Neville explained.

"We're not negotiating, Potter," Ginny added.

Harry took a deep breath and blew it out. "I can see that."

"The Triwizard Tournament!" Ron half-shouted.

Hermione, sitting next to him, half-leapt from her seat. "Ron! What are you talking about?"

"The tournament! It's a perfect opportunity to start," Ron said, turning to Harry with a tight grin. "You need to win this tournament and convince everyone they'd have to be barking mad to cross wands with the Boy Who Lived."

One consolation to the whole sorry mess was a decided lack of enmity from the Hufflepuffs. Having no idea that Cedric Diggory 'should' have been the Hogwarts Champion, they were cautiously supportive of Harry as the Hogwarts representative. Harry could appreciate small mercies, as the Slytherins were even worse. The house pretty much uniformly supported Draco Malfoy, still spreading rumours that he'd been unfairly expelled.

Harry almost laughed out loud when he saw the buttons make an appearance. Simply displaying "Draco Malfoy – Triwizard Champion" bordering with Durmstrang's colours, they were innocuous enough since they didn't directly attack the Hogwarts Champion. They were sufficient to make Professor McGonagall scowl ferociously, but she couldn't very well tell students off for choosing to support someone other than the Hogwarts Champion. Harry imagined anything nastier would have been confiscated by Professor Slughorn, earning the wearer a lecture on practising subtlety.

Still, while things were tense, they weren't as openly hostile as Harry remembered, for which he was grateful.

The Beauxbatons contingent returned to the Gryffindor table for lunch. While they were a little more guarded in their speech, the mood was still basically friendly. Harry did, however, notice Fleur eyeing him speculatively on a few occasions. He supposed between Millicent's observations before she transferred and the newspaper articles regarding the Dementor battle, there was no chance the French witch would ever dismiss him as a 'leetle boy' this time around. While nice for his ego, overall Harry would prefer to be underestimated by his competitors.

Harry was feeling distinctly unsettled as they headed back to the Gryffindor common room after lunch. He was sailing in relatively uncharted waters now, with only a single champion the same as in the original timeline. Ron's plan was going to shake things up even more. He and Hermione seemed to have a few ideas, but Ginny seemed far less enthusiastic.

As soon as they make their way past the Fat Lady's portrait Harry was confronted by a pale-faced Colin Creevey. "H-Harry? Can I talk to you for a moment?"

Harry felt a frisson of dread as he met the boy's red-rimmed eyes. "What is it Colin?" he asked. With everything that had happened to date, he wasn't too keen on going off with people he didn't fully trust.

The third-year's eyes darted to Harry's friends and back. With a visible effort, he swallowed. "I… I didn't mean to disrespect your parents Harry."

It all came together in an instant. "You put my name in the Goblet," Harry said. It wasn't a question.

Colin nodded jerkily and started to speak. "I just—"

A blur of red hair passed by Harry on the right and there was a loud smack as Ginny's fist impacted Colin's left cheek. The third-year boy's head snapped back and he tumbled onto his side. The sound barely registered with Harry as he darted forward and wrapped both arms around Ginny's midsection, hauling her backwards and up off of her feet. Her follow-up kick missed Colin's stomach by inches.

Harry held her tight while Ginny raged. He was just grateful she realized it was him holding her and refrained from throwing elbows at him. As her struggles lessened, Ron and Neville grabbed Colin by the arms and helped him up. Harry noticed that they didn't let go once Colin was on his feet. Harry took another half-step back, glad there didn't seem to be any prefects around at the moment. "How did you get my name… wait. You kept that essay, didn't you?"

"I'm sorry," Colin choked out, his face already starting to redden and swell, "I just thought you were being modest… and I wanted Hogwarts to win," he admitted.

"It still should have been my choice," Harry said as Ginny quieted. He could still feel her practically quivering with rage, so he didn't loosen his hold much.

"Colin," she hissed, "if anything happens to Harry in this tournament, I'll make you and your little brother pay!"

The third year went white as Harry let out a shocked choke. "Ginny!" he hissed.

"I mean it. If you get k-killed in this stupid tournament, he's as good as m-murdered you himself," she raged.

Harry tightened his arms around her, bringing his arms up around hers in a reversed hug. He held her there for a long moment before she let out a strangled sob and twisted to face him, burying her face in his chest. Luna came up from behind Harry and began rubbing the girl's back.

Harry was dimly aware of Hermione passing on the other side, marching up to Colin. "Ronald, Neville, please follow me," she said after a moment. Her voice was like iron.

"Uh, where are we going Hermione?" Ron asked, a little wide-eyed at her expression.

"Professor McGonagall," she replied.

As the four of them left, Ron and Neville kept hold of Colin's arms, even though he showed no signs of resistance whatsoever. After a moment, Harry led Ginny over to one of the couches. He sat at one end with Luna on the other and Ginny in between. She scooted over until their legs were touching, so Harry laid his arm across her shoulders, letting her lean into his side. It always surprised him, just a little bit, when he realized how small she really was.

After a long moment, Harry spoke. "I thought you liked Ron's idea?"

She shrugged. "If you are going to be forced to compete in this stupid tournament, yeah. But you originally preferred to give the whole thing a miss, didn't you?"

Harry nodded. "Yeah, my nice quiet year. Bollocks." He took a deep breath. "Involving Dennis might be a bit over the top?"

"Colin doesn't know I'm bluffing." Harry relaxed a little. "I want him to feel some of the anxiety he'd bought the rest of us with his utter stupidity," she continued.

"I'm pretty sure he takes you seriously now," Luna observed.

They sat quietly for several minutes until Hermione and the boys returned. "Two weeks suspension," she reported without preamble. "She's apparating him home to speak to his parents as soon as they have his trunk."

"It should have been longer," Ginny groused.

"He's also been instructed when he returns to have no personal interaction with Harry whatsoever," Hermione added.

Harry nodded. That would likely be torture.

"At least he didn't say anything about where he got the shiner," Ron added. "So you're not in any trouble, Ginny."

She nodded at her brother, but didn't say anything.

"I imagine he rather thought he deserved it," Hermione observed.

"That's because he did," Neville grumped.

Ginny was quiet the rest of the day; no surprise there for Harry. While he was, on one hand, gratified by her ferocity on his behalf, her anger was a bit daunting. Still, he tried to let her know he appreciated it without being too obvious. Though the bluff about Dennis was just a bit over the top and shocked him a little.

Then again, he wondered how he would react if someone had somehow entered Ginny into the tournament and then abruptly felt like a hypocrite.

Harry went to bed wondering if the tournament was one of those sticky parallels. He stopped Barty Crouch Jr. from entering his name, only to have Colin Creevey, of all people, do the deed. It didn't escape his notice that the Goblet hadn't needed a Confundus to pick Harry as a fourth champion from another school. It had picked him as the best Hogwarts had to offer, perversely proving the prat to be perspicacious.

Harry had no doubt the semi-sentient Goblet had picked up on his altered magical core. He likely had greater raw magical power than any of the other students. While that didn't make him smarter or more skilled, it was something the artefact was uniquely able to measure. Presumably someone with poor spell knowledge wouldn't enter themselves to avoid embarrassment.

Or maybe it could also sense his expanded memories, a thought that sent a shiver down Harry's spine. He gathered the duvet tighter around him to ward off the sudden chill.

Professor Slughorn was more than willing to let Harry leave class to attend the Weighing of the Wands. He was pleasantly surprised to see Ginny and Luna sent to collect him in Colin's place.

"No one travels alone if we can help it," Ginny explained. "We had a free hour, so we hung around the classroom where you said it would be and asked Mr. Bagman if he knew you were currently in class…"

"And so he asked you two to fetch me?" Harry asked with a smile. "Very clever!" he said in an admiring tone.

That earned him a small blush as they made their way to the ceremony.

The other champions had already arrived, no doubt brought by their respective headmasters. Fleur gave him a smile and a nod, while Draco was as unnervingly impassive as before. Harry's smile when he saw Rita Skeeter next to Ludo was not entirely forced. She wasn't the nicest person and no model of journalistic integrity, but she'd honoured their deal and even exceeded his expectations at times. That put her ahead of a depressingly large number of the adults Harry knew.

"Ah! Here he is, the Hogwarts champion! In you come, Harry, nothing to worry about. Just the wand weighing ceremony – the judges will be down soon with Mr. Ollivander. Miss Skeeter here is doing a small piece for the Daily Prophet," Bagman explained.

"Harry and I are old friends," Rita purred. "I wonder if I could have a word, maybe get some colour for my piece?"

"Certainly!" Ludo boomed. "Er, that is, if Harry has no objection?"

"I don't mind," Harry replied mildly, "though I think there might be better stories here today."

"Oh?" Rita asked, sidling closer as Ludo looked slightly alarmed. Harry idly wondered if she looked like this on Christmas morning. Harry's eyes moved past Draco. There was no way to bring up his expulsion without coming across as petty and he didn't doubt Rita was already fully aware.

Harry wondered how much gold it took Lucius to get the Prophet's editors to spike that story.

"I saw your piece last year about Miss Bulstrode and the transfer you helped arrange to Beauxbatons," Harry replied. "It turns out Fleur took her under her wing and helped her settle in at a new school. They're quite good friends now. Since the Triwizard Tournament is all about fostering international cooperation…"

"Oh yes," the reporter agreed, "practically writes itself." She moved over to Fleur, adopting what Harry knew was her least predatory smile.

The French champion looked somewhat alarmed before schooling her expression into a serene smile and began answering questions.

Rita maintained an affable demeanour when a somewhat alarmed Madame Maxime arrived and interjected herself into the conversation. The reporter merely turned to the large woman and asked a few questions that appeared to pleasantly surprise the headmistress.

The actual ceremony went mostly as Harry remembered, though he wondered if there was a slight frown on Ollivander's face when he used Harry's wand to create a fountain of wine.

Harry also noted, with some satisfaction, that Rita didn't seem to react to Fleur announcing that the Veela hair in her wand was that of her grandmother.

Of course, that didn't stop Fleur from tracking him down once they were dismissed and practically dragging him into a disused corridor. Harry discreetly waved off Ginny and Luna, who hung back as they followed.

"Why did you point zat… reporter… at me?" she demanded. Harry was actually surprised – he had no idea Rita's reputation had spread that widely.

"Relax," he said. "Remember that she started the ball rolling publicly, with her story about Millicent. Now she gets to do a follow-up piece patting herself on the back with how well she's doing now. You're going to want that goodwill once the Tournament starts, especially if you outperform the other champions – who were both born British. At that point a lot of the press might want to turn ugly… but Rita, bless her black little heart, likes to play favourites."

Fleur eyed him sceptically. "But if she is such a… 'ow do you know she will, as you say, play along?"

Harry shrugged. "I'm blackmailing her."

Fleur blinked.

"I know something about her that would land her in a lot of hot water," Harry explained. "She doesn't make up lies about me, I don't tell the truth about her. And I occasionally feed her a story that she knows will be true."

"Zat's how you helped Millicent."

Harry nodded.

Fleur eyed Harry for a moment and then smirked. "Zis Skeeter woman will now be 'ounding Millie for a follow-up interview now. I zink it likely she will hex you for that, mon ami."

"Not at all," Harry replied, shaking his head. "I think she will welcome the opportunity to pay you back a little. She hates nothing more than feeling like she owes someone."

Fleur laughed at that, the silvery peals echoing down the corridor. Ginny and Luna stuck their heads around the corner, one on top of the other. Harry gave them a cheery wave.

As the date of the first task approached, Harry made a point of taking long, leisurely flights around the castle grounds. If anyone asked, he said he missed flying because of the cancelled Quidditch season. He was also establishing an alibi. He wanted to confirm the dragons, since there would only be three champions. More importantly, he wanted to give Charlie Weasley plausible deniability if anyone accused him of tipping off his foster-brother.

Though Harry did wonder once if Charlie might be cheering for Harry's dragon to win. Then he dismissed the thought. Charlie wasn't that over-protective, was he?

He also worked on how to deal with the dragon in as impressive a manner as possible.

As expected, the evening after the last Hogsmeade Weekend before the first task, Harry spotted the enclosure near the Forbidden Forest with three dragons. As he circled a little lower, he wasn't surprised to see a Swedish Short-Snout, a Chinese Fireball and of course, a familiar-looking Hungarian Horntail.

No bets as to which one he'd end up with, he thought as he spiralled back upward.

Well away from the castle, Harry descended into a clearing he'd made far from curious eyes. A few flicks of his wand re-established the perimeter wards, then he began practising his transfiguration. Large-scale transfiguration.

Afternoon classes were cancelled the day of the first task. Harry found his nerves were quite sufficient to spoil his lunch, but forced himself to eat something. He planned to expend no small amount of magic. It wouldn't do to be lacking energy from an empty stomach. Ginny and the rest looked almost as nervous. Harry didn't envy them a bit.

Fleur was quiet but resolute. He'd confirmed that Madame Maxime had let her know about the first task. He wasn't taking any chances.

Finally, Professor McGonagall led Harry to the tent erected to block sight of the enclosure for the champions. She seemed just as ill-at-ease as Harry remembered.

"Just remember," she said as they approached the tent, "We have wizards standing by to control the situation if it gets out of hand. Just do your best and no one will think less of you."

"I will," Harry replied. "Maybe I can earn some extra credit for Transfiguration in there?"

The woman stopped dead in her tracks, eying him suspiciously. "I wasn't aware the champions had been informed about the first task."

Harry smiled. "I saw them wrangling three dragons in an enclosure not far from here. There's no roof, so anyone using a broom in this vicinity for the last three days knows. I've been flying every evening to reduce stress, so…"

McGonagall closed her eyes. "…and of course, no one thought of that. Just because they cancelled Quidditch, it's not like there isn't a castle full of students with brooms."

"I don't think a lot of things were thought of ahead of time," Harry suggested delicately.

"Right. Well, Mr. Potter I suppose with forewarning I should expect your usual standard of performance?"

"Yes, Professor McGonagall," Harry agreed with what he hoped was an innocent-looking smile.

"Scamp," she muttered under her breath as she left him at the entrance to the tent.

When Harry entered the tent, he saw Fleur and Draco sitting on stools at different corners, while Ludo Bagman held court in the centre. Harry couldn't figure out why he was still wearing his ill-fitting quidditch uniform from when he played on the Wimbourne Wasps. "Harry! Good-o! Come in, come in. Make yourself at home."

Harry did his best to tune out most of Ludo's chatter. He listened long enough to confirm the task was as he expected, then ignored the has-been. Of course, when it came time to draw the models from the sack, he ended up with the Hungarian Horntail again. He didn't mind; what he had planned would look even more impressive. As Fleur nervously followed Ludo out of the tent, Harry settled down on a stool in one corner. He sat perfectly still, never taking his eyes off of Draco.

Once they were alone, the blonde's customary sneer slowly reappeared like an unwelcome rash. "So, half-blood, ready to die like a brave Gryffindor today?"

Harry didn't respond.

"You know, Potter, you didn't seem that surprised about the dragons. Did your headmaster tip you off? Or one of your sycophants? No matter. I've known for weeks and I've had plenty of time to work out exactly how to put you in your place."

Harry stayed silent, but as he gazed at the former Slytherin, he let his mind wander back to his nightmares regarding Ginny. He felt his pulse quicken as his magic began to circulate. It started slowly at first, but steadily increased in tempo as the Durmstrang champion tried to get a reaction. Harry felt the hair of his fringe stir in the non-existent breeze.

Two high spots of colour bloomed under Draco's cheekbones as the murmurs of the crowd surged louder, then erupted into cheers. "Well, apparently the Veela bitch survived," Draco drawled. "That's too bad, it would make my performance all the more convincing if she was eaten and you were maimed. After all, breeding will tell…" He fell silent as the tent entrance stirred and Ludo reappeared to collect Draco.

Once he was alone, Harry concentrated more fully on pulling up his magic as much as he could. He barely registered the gasps and cries of alarm from the crowd outside. However, he snapped out of his meditations when there was a trumpeting roar of pain Harry knew without a doubt came from the Chinese Fireball. Loud squeals and cries followed, rising above the now quieter audience. As the cries gradually trailed off, there was some muted applause.

It was quite a while before Ludo came to collect Harry. The normally ebullient man was quiet as he led Harry out of the tent.

If anything, the Horntail seemed even angrier and more feral than Harry remembered. Then he saw the large gout of blood near the nest, pooled around a burn scar of something that looked like a strong corrosive acid poured onto the solid stone. The nest itself was surrounded by a litter of broken egg shells and smears of fluid. Harry felt his gorge rise. As the gate to the dragon pens swung shut, Harry got a glimpse of a stone platform levitated by a team of Dragon Handlers. Resting on the platform was the sprawled body of the Chinese Fireball, its upper face melted as if by a strong acid, both eyes burned away.

Hagrid stood off to one side of the handlers, the face above his beard as pale as milk.

The crowd slowly stirred as Harry paused, staring as the gate closed. He saw Draco standing unharmed next to a scowling Pomfrey, smirking.

Harry ground his teeth as the handlers got the nearly frenzied Horntail settled as best they could. He knew since the Fireball either died or had to be put down, the smell of death was all around his opponent, making his job even harder. Hagrid would never forgive him if he did lasting harm.

Whatever Bagman said was lost in the roar of blood in Harry's ears as he stepped into the enclosure. The noise of the crowd came up as the Horntail's head snapped around, orienting on Harry. The Boy Who Lived drew in a breath as he saw the dragon's hindquarters flex, preparing to launch it across the enclosure at this impudent insect that dared approach its precious eggs.

Harry's wand came up and snapped downward with a flick of his wrist. "Ferrum Torque!" he shouted as he hurled his magic at the ground. A short, thick iron chain appeared, one end bolted into the stone and the other end attached to a manacle clamped around the dragon's foreleg. Clearly confused, it tried to rear back but was brought up short.

Dragons are highly magic-resistant creatures; it normally requires an entire team of Dragon Handlers casting in tandem to stun one. But conjured manacles don't have to defeat that resistance. They just have to be strong enough to withstand the strength of a broody fifty-foot apex predator.

Harry had practised until his conjured chains were extremely sturdy.

As the off-balance Horntail planted its other forepaw to steady itself, Harry's wand snapped down again. "Ferrum Torque!" and another chain appear to manacle that leg. The dragon's head whipped around to look at the new chain and Harry cast again, chaining down the rear legs. The dragon hunched forward, straining to free its limbs and when its head passed low, another, bigger manacle appeared right behind the head, bound to the ground with a very short chain. A final cast pinned down the lashing tail.

The crowd grew silent at the sight of the massive dragon, awkwardly pinned to the stone floor of the enclosure. Its wings flapped futilely as it struggled against the chains. Harry eyed them cautiously, but they seemed to be holding up. He edged along the wall of the enclosure, staying well away from the area in front of the Horntail's head. It roared out a blast of fire anyway, making him cringe back, even as it fell far short.

Harry cautiously made his way to the nest. The cheers and applause from the crowd picked up as they seemed to catch on to what he was doing. As he circled around the angry mother, a flash of light and a loud crack drew his attention to the top-most of the real eggs. A piece of thick egg-shell spiralled up into the air as albumen exploded away from the side of the cracked shell. The smell that immediately struck him was ghastly, what was worse was the way the struggling Horntail suddenly went utterly still.

Harry's eyes widened in the instant before the Horntail went mad. Screaming with rage, it gave a full-body heave that cracked and split the scales under the manacles. The chains held for an instant before the one around its neck shattered, then one on a rear leg, then all of them in a blizzard of shrapnel that winked out of existence as the conjured forms were disrupted. The horntail surged to its feet, spinning to inspect its nest. Harry could see it gathering its breath and thickening its neck as it then turned toward him. Stunned, he did the first thing that came to mind and cast the strongest flame-freezing charm he could as the Horntail vomited forth a tsunami of flames.

Harry found himself suddenly airborne. His over-powered charm was strong enough to affect dragon-fire, making burning flames 'feel like a summer breeze' as Flitwick described it. But it rendered more than a breeze when dealing with this rage-induced inferno. While happily not incinerated, Harry was still blown off of his feet, tumbling backwards as the audience screamed in fear. He was glad he'd endured endless hours of falling drills as he tucked his head in and did a backwards shoulder-roll… thus, protecting his skull and his wand, not necessarily in that order, as he came up in a crouch.

The Horntail seemed to pause for a moment as the flames dissipated, revealing Harry Potter only slightly rumpled. Then it gathered its legs under it and prepared to crush the impudent human before it.

Harry knew he didn't have time or space to chain it down again. As it prepared to spring, he aimed his wand directly at its head and pushed every ounce of magic he could into his next and possibly last, spell.

"STUPEFY!"

A bar of red light a yard wide sprang into existence, connecting his wand with the Horntail's head. It fluoresced so brightly spectators could see afterimages when closing their eyelids fifteen minutes later.

Harry dropped his smoking wand and fell to his knees as grey spots danced in his vision.

The Hungarian Horntail collapsed in a boneless heap.

It didn't take long before Harry slowly climbed to his feet and retrieved the golden egg. The reek of the broken egg was horrid, but the glimpse he got of the half-formed hatchling within was even worse. He thought of Hagrid's Norbert and winced. He was halfway back to the entrance before the crowd seemed to shake itself awake and begin applauding. That seemed to jolt the dragon-handlers back into motion and they cautiously approached the stunned Horntail.

As the adrenalin began to wear off, Harry felt a headache coming on, not to mention a bone-deep weariness. He hadn't pushed his magic that hard in a while. He raised his wand and examined the tip, wincing at the scorch marks. "I need to do something about that," he thought, not for the first time. "This is only going to get worse as I get older. If I get older." He sighed. "Better not let Ginny hear me talk like that."

Surprisingly, Professor McGonagall was waiting for him at the contestant's entrance. "An unusual application of transfiguration. Full marks, Mr. Potter," she said with a small nod.

Harry smiled.

"You need to see Madam Pomfrey before you receive your score," she continued. "You are looking a bit strained, not that that's surprising. You expended quite a large amount of magic in a short period of time."

She led Harry to the first aid tent, where the healer eyed him, frowning. "I don't like your colour," she stated as she began waving her wand. "Definite signs of exhaustion. If I allow you to leave for your scores, will you refrain from any further magic today?"

Harry nodded. "I'm pretty knackered," he admitted.

"Good, remember that. I also want you to go to sleep early tonight, preferably after a good meal."

McGonagall snorted. Harry agreed, Gryffindor Tower was not going to be a quiet place tonight. He turned to his head of house. "Don't worry, I have silencing charms on my bed. Ron and Neville both snore."

As they made their way out of the tent, Harry's friends were waiting. He barely registered how pale they were looking before a streak of red impacted his chest.

"Whoof! Ginny?" he exclaimed. Her face was pressed to his sternum and her arms were wrapped so tightly around his ribs that oxygen was becoming an issue. Feeling acutely self-conscious, especially with the Professor right there, he settled his arms around her shoulders. Any awkwardness fled his mind when he realized how hard she was shaking.

"She's been like that since the chains broke," Ron explained. "Not that I blame her," he added quickly when Hermione narrowed her eyes at him.

"We all thought you were going to die," Luna explained.

"Luna!" Neville exclaimed.

"What? Didn't you say, 'Oh Merlin, he's going to die!'," Luna asked Neville. "It was quite surprising. But Harry, if you could stun the dragon, why wasn't that the main plan?"

"Er, I didn't know I could do that," Harry admitted, "I sort of panicked at the last minute."

"Oh. So, you thought you were going to die too," Luna concluded. She smiled. "I'm rather glad you didn't."

Ginny let out a muffled sound somewhere between a sob and a laugh.

Eventually Professor McGonagall corralled Harry and led him in front of the judges on their raised seats draped in gold. It took a bit for Ginny to calm down enough to let him go. Not that he begrudged her. He had some idea of what she was feeling, after all. That nightmare never seemed to get old.

Madame Maxime raised her wand, launching a silver ribbon into the air that formed the number nine. The crowd applauded.

Mr. Throckmorton, looking a little shell-shocked, actually gave Harry a ten. The applause grew louder.

Professor Dumbledore also gave Harry a ten, which surprised him a little. The crowd started cheering now.

Ludo Bagman gave Harry his third ten, which didn't surprise him at all. Harry wasn't sure it could get any louder.

Then Severus Snape raised his wand into the air, glancing directly at Harry and gave him a two. There was a pause, then the booing started.

The agent in place carefully folded the invisibility cloak and with shaking hands slid it into the secret compartment on the underside of his trunk. That had been too close. He'd followed his instructions in what he thought was a creative manner,but he hadn't counted on the raw violence of the enraged horntail. No sooner had his piercing charm cracked the shell then the damn beast was breaking loose from Potter's conjured chains. What he hadn't expected was the flood of flames that it produced. Fortunately, Potter went with a flame-freezing charm, rather than a less effective shield. Otherwise at the minimum his cloak would have been lit on fire from the backwash. As it was, the cloak had been blown about him, but any glimpses of him that caused would have been obscured by the charmed flames. Still, it had been too close.

Fortunately, between the cloak, the silencing charms on his shoes and the scent-masking charms, he had remained undetected. And he'd almost succeeded in achieving his objective.

"I can't believe that utter bastard!" Ron raged as they walked past the Fat Lady and into Gryffindor tower. "He gave you a two for winning! A ruddy two!"

"He justified it by saying that Harry's magic damaged the egg," Hermione explained. "I asked Professor McGonagall afterwards, who heard it from Professor Dumbledore."

"But he never cast a spell at it!" Ron protested as the Gryffindors grabbed a pair of couches near the fireplace. Most of their housemates were still at dinner or filtering back through the hallways. Harry was not too proud to admit he'd eaten as quickly as manners permitted and fled the Great Hall as soon as he could.

"He claimed it was accidental magic, since Harry has 'a history of poor self-control'," Hermione added.

"That's utter bollocks!" Ron snarled.

"Don't shoot the messenger!" Hermione snapped. "I'm just repeating what I was told. I personally think it's utter rubbish, given that he gave Draco a perfect score, saying it wasn't his fault 'the stupid beast destroyed its own eggs'."

"I'm not mad at you, Hermione," Ron hastily assured her. "I'm just frustrated that he's getting away with it."

"Well, the other judges clearly didn't agree," Hermione pointed out. "His other scores were low enough to leave him in third place, behind Fleur and Harry."

"What did Draco do to the Chinese Fireball?" Harry asked. He needed to distract himself from the unfairness of it all. He didn't mind being a point behind Fleur, if only it wasn't due to Snape. It was amusing to see her literally mobbed with well-wishers for taking first place. Veela charm plus unexpected competence was evidently a big draw. Not many people could enchant a broody dragon to make it fall asleep and leave its eggs unguarded.

"He banished something at its face," Neville said, watching Hermione and Ron slowly cool down. "Whatever it was must have been extremely corrosive."

"The poor thing was blinded immediately," Luna added in a sad tone. "Then it collapsed and in its death throes it crushed all of its eggs."

"It was a vial of something," Ginny said thoughtfully. "I saw light glinting off of what looked like glass." Harry was a little surprised, until he remembered that she possessed good enough eyesight to fill in for him as Gryffindor Seeker, in a time that never was. Harry squeezed her hand. She'd been subdued all through the evening meal and he was a little concerned.

"What potion could do that?" Ron asked, turning to Hermione, who was just starting to calm down herself.

"Why are you asking me?" she demanded.

"Because you're smarter than me and know practically everything there is to know," Ron replied matter-of-factly.

Hermione's mouth dropped open, clearly not expecting such a blatant compliment after a semi-row.

"He has a point, Hermione," Harry added. "I can't think of anything that could do that, but you've always been more knowledgeable about potions than I am."

"I can't think of anything," she said slowly, "even in the N.E.W.T. potions curriculum." She broke off as she noticed Ron's grin. "I just skimmed it over the summer to get a better idea of what is possible," she added with some exasperation in her voice.

"Then I think it's safe to say there's no way Draco learned to brew that on his own," Harry concluded.

"Snape brewed it for him," Ron and Neville said, practically in unison.

"You know," Harry snarked. "It's almost making me nostalgic. Snape tells Draco what the task is, then gives him a plan to defeat it. Even brews the potion for him. All Draco has to do is master the Banishing Charm, which is already on the fourth-year curriculum."

"And as a judge he's covering for him and clearly biasing the scores in his favour," Neville added.

"It's almost like he's teaching potions again," Ron groused.

"Cheating as usual… wait," Harry said, thinking hard. "Didn't Snape put all of the Durmstrang slips into the Goblet of Fire?"

"Why would that…" Hermione's voice trailed off. "Oh, he wouldn't!"

"It would explain why he was chosen over someone more competent, like, say, Victor Krum," Harry allowed drily.

"You mean to tell me he replaced their entries with ones that all said Draco Malfoy?" Ron demanded, outraged.

"Honestly, Ron, does that really surprise you?" Hermione asked.

Ron subsided. "I suppose not, I just can't understand…"

"How he can be so foul?" Hermione supplied.

"Yeah," he admitted. "I know, I know, I shouldn't be surprised."

"Evil is hard to understand sometimes," Harry mused. "Your parents raised you right, so it's unnatural for you to think that way."

"You figured it out," Ron pointed out.

"I had far worse examples growing up. I've… seen… enough that very little can surprise me anymore," Harry said with a shrug.

Ron looked away, cheeks colouring.

"That doesn't mean you aren't a good person too!" Ginny objected.

"Don't confuse being polite with being nice; I can be pretty ruthless when I I need to be," Harry said in a low voice. "I think that's why Professor Dumbledore reacts the way he does."

"Well, he's doing so out of ignorance," Ginny shot back, a slow flush rising on her cheeks.

"And we're very glad he stays that way," Hermione reminded them in a terse whisper, "or have you forgotten?"

The conversation cut off as the portrait opened again, admitting a large group of chattering Gryffindors who let out a cheer when they saw Harry. The common room grew a bit loud as the party started and everyone that hadn't congratulated him at dinner came to pay their respects. Harry tried to greet them with some enthusiasm, but it grew harder to do as his headache came back. Between his fatigue and a very large dinner he was not inclined to move any time soon, though he did intend to keep his promise to Madam Pomfrey and retire early. He also pretended not to notice the seam on his Golden Egg. He had no wish to add to the cacophony.

Through it all, Ginny stayed glued to his side. Harry couldn't really blame her, she must have had a bad shock when the chains snapped. It had been harder than he expected, getting used to people worrying about him again. A little bumping of elbows was a small price to pay. Not that he really minded, he admitted to himself. Sod her overprotective brother.

After a while and a few less than subtle attempts to reel her into the conversation, Ginny seemed to return to her normal outgoing self. But her shoulder never left his.

The next day, Harry awoke very groggy, but at least the bone-deep weariness of the previous evening was done. It still took most of their morning exercises to feel back to normal again. After a large breakfast, he suggested they pay a call on Hagrid. He hadn't been seen in the Great Hall since the first task ,but Harry remembered him standing with the dragon handlers with a face like a wet weekend as they hauled off the poor Chinese Fireball.

At least there was smoke coming from the short chimney when they arrived, so they knew he was around. After Ron knocked, there was some shuffling and Hagrid opened the door, looking rather unkempt. "Ron, Harry, what 'r yeh lot doing 'ere?"

"We came by to see if you were all right," Hermione answered, peering at him. "After what, er, happened," she added lamely.

Hagrid's face sagged a bit. "Oh, terrible business that. Well, come on in, got th' kettle on. Charlie came over for a cuppa."

Harry tensed up a bit as they filed in. He wasn't sure he was up for dealing with Ginny's overprotective brother this morning, but the redhead seemed very subdued as he sat at the rough-hewn table. Harry idly wondered if he was a little hung over. Once Hagrid was done being mother and everyone had politely declined the offer of Rock Cakes, he settled onto his own chair.

"I do want t' say I'm proud of yeh, Harry," Hagrid said after a moment, "You and that French lass went out ter' the way not to hurt th' poor things." He paused a moment to sniff. "It weren't your fault someone hexed that egg, but you'll be glad t' know the Horntail is awake again and jes' fine."

"Well that's good," Harry agreed. "Wait. You know it was hexed?"

"Plain as day," Charlie growled. "When we examined the shell pieces it was obviously a piercing hex. Someone got through their wards and did it deliberately to goad her."

Harry frowned. He supposed it wasn't too far-fetched for Snape or Malfoy to arrange someone to sabotage him.

"Snape claimed it was accidental magic," Ron groused.

"He tried that shite with my boss," the dragon handler snorted. "He pulled out the shell pieces and damn near made the greasy bastard eat them. We're billing them for two intentional killings."

"What do you mean?" Hermione asked.

"This was supposed to be a non-lethal contest, otherwise we'd never have agreed to supply clutching mothers. We lost one of nineteen adult Fireballs in western preserves! Not to mention a full clutch," Charlie added bitterly.

Hermione was aghast. "But… why did you agree if they are so rare?"

"Politics. The tournament organizers wanted an exotic variety and they put a lot of pressure on us to cooperate through the Romanian ministry. Most of those half-wits went to Durmstrang, so the fix was in." Charlie snarled. "But at least we got an agreement regarding safety precautions beforehand. Unless they weasel out of it some way, the penalty clauses should fund our reserve for the next three years."

Harry also noted Luna was also looking distressed. Neville quietly took her hand.

"I still can' believe they did somethin' so cruel," Hagrid said, looking down into his bucket of tea.

"Did you forget he tried to kill Harry second year," Ron said, only to quiet down when Hermione gave him a sharp look.

"Draco's a vicious little thug," Harry opined, "but right now it's Snape that's making him dangerous."

"You still need to be careful around him," Ginny reminded him.

Harry scowled. "…and maybe he needs to be careful around me."

The conversation gradually moved on to happier topics. Hagrid told stories of all the things he and Charlie had gotten up to when he was a student, some of which were quite amusing. Charlie in turn told stories from the Dragon Preserve, some of which were quite alarming. Harry realized, in his own way, Charlie was just as crazy as Hagrid, at least where dragons were concerned.

All in all, it was a pleasant time and slowly Hagrid began to look less morose. Harry supposed it was the half-giant's own good nature, but he seemed to always be inordinately dismayed when confronting the cruelty of others. He recalled from the original timeline the man's staunch defence of Snape on Professor Dumbledore's word… right up until the greasy bastard murdered the headmaster. But if all it required was some company and friendly conversation to restore the kind man's spirits, it was well worth the time.

Finally, the siren call of unfinished homework and luncheon in the Great Hall made itself heard, so Harry and his friends bade the groundskeeper farewell. As they began to make their way back, Harry heard a voice calling after him. Glancing back, he saw Charlie catching up to them.

"A word, Harry?" The elder Weasley asked.

Harry nodded cautiously. When Charlie glanced at the others, Harry guessed his hesitation and gave them a nod. Hermione led them further up the path, but not out of sight. Harry didn't miss the cool gaze Ginny gave her brother.

Harry casually flicked his wand, erecting a simple privacy ward that would conceal their conversation. "Yes?"

"All right, I'll come right out with it. What is the story on that murdering little shite?"

"Draco?"

"Yes. Him. I know Snape likely brewed the acid, but Malfoy is the one who delivered it. He's also the one sporting a sick little smirk as he did it and the Fireball started screaming. We were required to wait until the judges dropped the ward, so I had plenty of time to memorize his expression." The redhead's face was flushed with anger and his hands kept clenching into tight fists, making the cords in his forearms jump and writhe. "You know something," Charlie accused, "something about that little shite and I want to know what it is."

Harry knew Charlie wasn't angry at him. He even agreed when Hagrid thanked him for trying to avoid hurting the Hungarian Horntail. But Harry found it hard not to snap back. It didn't help that the question tapped into a wellspring of rage Harry barely kept a lid on. "It's less something he's done," he said tersely, "as something he might do again."

Charlie went very still as his face paled. "What. Did. He. Do?" he ground out.

"I don't know for sure," Harry began, "other than they were both at the Sacking of Hogwarts. But from the condition of her… body… whoever killed Ginny t-took their time about it. I never found Draco after that, but I know that beforehand he was aware of our… relationship." Harry closed his eyes, ramming down the magic that wanted to erupt and destroy the clearing in a paroxysm of rage. "But part of me… knows… he did it. He caused the incursion that killed Dumbledore. I have no doubt he was there to finish the job. Nothing he has done since I came back has made me think any different."

Charlie's eyes were now flat, assessing. "You aren't going to let history repeat itself, even if it means breaking it off with her," Charlie demanded.

Harry ignored the latter sentiment, focusing on the former. "If he tries to hurt her again, I will be the end of him."

He was quiet as he re-joined his friends and entered the Great Hall for lunch. Charlie's impromptu inquisition stirred up a lot of ugly memories and emotions best left undisturbed. An angry, paranoid corner of his soul wanted to just walk over to Draco and end him right there. Before he could do any more harm.

Finally, Ginny had enough of his brooding. "I think my brother needs a thorough hexing," she declared.

Ron's head jerked up from his focus on his food, frowning.

"Not you, Ron," Ginny said. "Charlie. Either that or forbid him talking to Harry. Every time he does, he leaves Harry a complete mess."

"It's not him," Harry reassured her. "Not really," he responded to her sceptical look. Harry lowered his voice. "He asked me about Draco, and that always puts me in a foul mood."

Ginny shrugged. "No surprise there. Try to think of something happier though. Like Draco's face when he sees tomorrow's Daily Prophet."

Sure enough, the following morning the daily owl deliveries left the breakfast tables abuzz as they read the latest edition of the Prohpet.

"POTTER'S STUNNING VICTORY!" the headline trumpeted. The rest of the page was dominated by an animated picture of Harry raising his wand and casting as the enraged Horntail bore down on him. Mortified as he was, Harry had to admit it did look rather impressive. Even if a bit overdramatic.

Ron gave Harry a smug look. Harry sighed and nodded. It looked like his friend's idea just might work. He just hoped it had a discouraging effect in the future. With the legend of precociousness he'd developed to cover any slip-ups, it was unlikely he could count on future enemies underestimating him. So, he really had little to lose in that respect.

"Harry," Hermione said, interrupting his thoughts. He looked over to where his bushy-haired friend was poring over the inside sections. "There's an opinion piece in here calling out some of the 'obviously biased' judgments displayed at the first task. The author is calling for a Ministry investigation into allegations of favouritism."

Harry's eyes widened. "I'm surprised someone at the head table hasn't spontaneously combusted," he murmured.

Hermione cleared her throat primly. "At least someone might have to display a more even-handed approach going forward if they want to avoid a scandal," she offered.

"Perhaps," Harry agreed. He had little doubt the Durmstrang headmaster would find another way. "Speaking of bias," he continued, gesturing at the paper, "I didn't win the event yesterday, Fleur did."

"It might refer to the fact that you still won against the dragon," Neville ventured, "even after you were sabotaged."

"I suppose that's true," Harry agreed. But he wondered if that would still be true if he and Fleur swapped schools and nationalities. At least the Beauxbatons students didn't seem to hold it against him. Maybe Neville was right.

A/N by worfe: This is a small interlude I wrote from the "Nightmares of Futures Past" world by S'Tarkan. Bloody wonderful fic, and if you're reading this then you must agree. (Because honestly, who else but fans would trouble themselves with this oneshot.) When reading the fic I was struck with this idea and it wouldn't leave me alone. Harry has had some bad dreams, but he usually wakes up screaming, not crying. However, one night he did. What would Ron's reaction be if he heard? Indeed, the structure of the plot makes me wonder if Ron might have. This is my take on what might have happened that night. Published with author's permission. Thanks S'Tarkan for your advice.

Context: Sometime during chapter 15, not long after Harry moves in with the Weasleys.

Ron's mind slowly emerged from sleep. It was a hazy journey and not one he was sure he wanted to be taking. It was summer and a faint breeze was blowing across his face in a most gentle manner. Almost like how his mother's hand had toyed with his hair when he'd been little and unable to sleep. Being in his own room, in his own familiar bed, it would be rather easy to go back to sleep. But for some reason a part of him seemed to be prodding him, telling him he needed to wake up. After a moment his mind cleared a bit and he was able to realize that it had been a noise which had pulled him out of his sleep. And it wasn't a night sound he was familiar with.

When one spent most of the year sharing a dormitory with four other boys, well, one became accustomed to sounds that could wake you in the middle of the night. Neville had a soft puttering snore, Dean sometimes talked in his sleep and Seamus would almost always wake up around 2 a.m. for a drink of water from the bathroom faucet. Ron had been told that he snored; he didn't believe it. Harry's bed was always silent; oddly enough this lack of noise seemed to bother Ron more than any of the other sounds. The youngest Weasley boy knew full well that Harry's silence was made by spells and hid the nightmares his friend seemed to wrestle with nightly. Even still, it wasn't unusual for Ron to occasionally wake in the early hours of the morning to see Harry's thin silhouette leaving their room.

Now, since Harry had come to live with them, he'd been sharing a room with the raven haired boy sans silencing charms. Their first night as 'roomies', the previous evening, he'd awoken to find his bed rattling as if a giant had seized the Burrow and was shaking it like a tambourine. Indeed it had taken a moment for the startled red head to realize that wasn't the case. When he'd finally shaken the cotton out of his skull, he'd jumped into action. Ron had jostled Harry awake only—but Harry's eyes had burst open at the lightest touch, the green orbs glowing with power. But while that power had been somewhat intimidating, Ron hadn't even considered backing away. The look of terror had filled him with concern. When Harry had reluctantly, and furiously, revealed the contents of his nightmare, Ron had been at a complete loss. The Burrow burning to the ground? His Mum still inside? That was a terrible, impossible dream. Why did Harry dream those things? Was he really so paranoid that he'd worry about the safety of the Burrow? Ron knew Harry was careful, and perhaps with good reason…but why would he dream those things? Sure, perhaps Hogwarts was dangerous but this was the Burrow.

Still, it had taken him a little longer than usual to fall back asleep that night.

The next day, under the comforting brightness of the sun, Ron had managed to let go of Harry's fears. He was able to brush them off as some sort of lingering badness. Harry had been given a tough life, the murder of his parents, living with those monstrous muggles, being attacked by Slytherins and You-Know-Who. Perhaps it was no wonder Harry had those kinds of dreams about his new home. But nothing bad would happen here.

Still, this clearer mind made Ron, for the first time, really worry about Harry.

No, that wasn't right, he'd indeed worried over his friend's physical safety many times before. Indeed it could be said that worrying about Harry was a hobby that he, Hermione and Neville had all picked up over their first year of Hogwarts. During the year they worried about Slytherins attacking, both the student and teacher variety. During the summer Ron's own particular concern had sparked his and the twins' rescue mission. But now this worry was very different. Ron found himself wondering if his best mate was, in fact, 'alright' as the young man claimed. Perhaps there was damage deeper than you could see.

Not that Harry didn't have a good reason for it, Ron's mind was quick to add that detail. After finding Harry on that bed at the Dursleys…Merlin he'd never forget that for as long as he lived. Seeing Harry on the bed, so bent and broken. Well, ever since finding Harry there, something about his view had changed. When Harry had managed to take on Malfoy, Crabbe and Goyle on the Express, Ron had looked up to his new mate as pretty near unbeatable. The Boy Who Lived was legend, after all, and Harry Potter lived up to the name. Then on Halloween, Harry had managed to kill a fully grown mountain troll. That same night his mother's lecture had explained, very loudly, that most adult wizards couldn't have handled a situation like that. Course, Mum hadn't exactly been proud. But Harry had managed, coming out with only a broken arm. He'd even been in good enough spirits to joke with the twins the next day, even though he had nearly died. The thought of Harry nearly dying had been enough to keep Ron up sleepless, yet it didn't seem to trouble Harry. Yep, his friend was pretty amazing.

But to see him lying on that bed, you'd never think that Harry Potter was unbreakable ever again. He had lied there so still, so swollen and purple with bruises. His voice had been whisper soft and scratchy as sand paper when he'd asked for water. The pleading tone as he asked for something to drink had nearly brought Ron to his knees. When he had noticed a scrap of cloth in his friend's hand he had wondered for a moment, until he recognized the scarf Ginny had made Harry for Christmas. He was forced to look away when he realized Harry had been clutching to the poorly knitted gift like it was a lifeline.

But then Harry had seemed fine.

When he and Ginny had finally managed to work their way into Harry's hospital room, the young man had been seated up in bed smiling and cracking jokes. And it hadn't been fake cheerfulness either. Ron might not be an expert when it came to emotional stuff, Hermione would be first in line to agree to that statement. But he thought he knew his friend well enough to know when he was faking. Ginny seemed to know the real Harry too. Although how she could from a few ruddy letters was beyond him.

What had surprised him the most had been Harry's rational outlook on everything. Ron hadn't expected that. Sitting at the Burrow, the floo powder locked away, there wasn't much else to do except sit around and worry over how Harry was doing. He'd tried guessing how his friend would be feeling, and he'd been hard pressed to settle on what Harry's mood would be. So, he'd settled on trying to figure out how he'd feel if it had been him lying on that bed. Ron had a hard time putting himself in Harry's place but he was pretty sure he'd be utterly pissed at the unfairness of it all. But Harry's cool logical assessment had been a surprise. And while it hadn't been expected, Ron found he'd been oddly relieved. This was the Harry he was used to. Harry was strong.

Which was why he hated wondering if there was something more the matter with his friend. He didn't even want to think the words, didn't even want to consider if something was perhaps…well, if his friend was a little loopy. He felt like a traitor for even considering it. But those nightmares couldn't be normal. And while Harry seemed to find being normal an impossibility…just maybe there was something wrong with his friend. But Ron tried to banish those thoughts away. He told himself it was loyalty, real friends wouldn't think that. Gryffindors wouldn't turn on their own like that. But some part of him knew it was also avoidance. He didn't want to face that sort of problem. Being Harry's friend had meant facing things quicker than he'd have expected but he didn't think he was quite ready to handle that. And while they might be new to him, Harry had parents now. Maybe it wasn't official or anything but surely his Mum and Dad would help Harry if he needed help, right?

But now it was the second night they'd shared a room, with no silencing charms to block out the noises Harry made. And Ron had awoken to a strange noise, one which he had never heard in the night before. In the bed across from his, Ron heard Harry crying. But it wasn't crying exactly, or at least not like anything Ron would consider crying. There was such a primal quality to it, such a deep deep sadness. The noise seemed to fill their small room up with misery.

Lying awake listening to the sobs that racked Harry's body, Ron came across a clear bit of knowledge about himself and his life. He was very lucky; he'd never known this kind of emotion before. Oh, Ron had cried; he wouldn't exactly publish that information for all of Hogwarts to read, but he remembered crying, well…like a baby when he was little. He'd cried when the twins had played a particularly cruel trick involving his favorite bear and a spider. He'd really cried when he'd fallen off a broom and broken his arm, he must have cried during his entire time at St. Mungo's, perhaps even after the healer had mended his arm. But he'd never cried like Harry was crying. The noise coming from Harry was more painful than crying, the word didn't even begin to describe the flood of pain that was seeping from his friend.

And in the face of this brokenness Ron found himself frozen. He thought he knew what he should do, this was the time you offered comfort, right? At the very least he should ask him what was wrong or tell him it would be okay. But somehow Ron couldn't do any of this. He was ashamed to say that he couldn't face this vicious outpouring of emotion. He lied there selfishly wishing that he hadn't woken up. He wasn't old enough to understand this sort of grief.

Grief was the word for what this was. Ron had heard the word before; it was a word that in his mind had come to mean his uncles Fabian and Gideon. It was the reason he didn't ask his Mum about them, even though he'd been somewhat curious about them, how they had died. It was the reason his own twin brothers, whose names also began with F and G, would occasionally bring a wispy sort of sadness to his mother's eyes, a sadness which had nothing to do with their dreadful grades. There were some things that families didn't mention. Not because they forgot, but because they remembered and the remembering seemed to hurt. Not that Ron could remember his long dead uncles, but he could taste traces of the pain their passing had left. Once, when he was little, his mother had been cleaning their house and had stumbled upon a thick winter robe buried in the bottom of their coat closet, with the initials GTP stitched along the inside collar with a distinctive flourish Ron knew to be his Mum's. She had held the thick material to her face and wept from someplace deep inside. The noise had come more from her gut than her throat. Ron, five or six at the time, had hid in his room. It had scared him then.

And strangely, as soon as he named it and knew it, Ron thought it seemed like Harry's sobs began to slacken. He continued to listen to Harry's ragged breathing for a moment, wondering if he could talk to his friend now. But whatever Harry had just experienced seemed so personal and separate from anything Ron had experienced. Should he say something? He wanted to help his friend but he'd suddenly been confronted with the realization that whatever Harry's demons were, they weren't something Ron had ever touched upon.

In the darkened room, Ron bit his lip as he watched Harry shakily rise to his feet and move towards the door. Now was the time to say something, if there was anything to be said. But somehow, lying in his bed in the dark, Ron couldn't get up the courage to say—not a word, not a single word.

Soon Harry was gone. Ron could barely hear Harry's footsteps as his best mate stealthily slipped down the stairs.

His moment had left. Ron lied on his small bed and found himself filled with an odd feeling of disappointment. He turned onto his side, punching his pillow viciously, and stared into the wall. He'd been a coward and he'd let Harry down.

Ron knew he'd failed the one motto Harry had taught him. Gryffindors look out for their own. And as he glared into the dark he became consumed with a determination to never let Harry down again. He didn't know what sort of person he'd have become if he'd never met Harry Potter that day on the train. He didn't want to know. And he might have been weak tonight, but this would be the last night.

Filled with this sense of focus, a sort he'd never felt before, Ron came to another insight. Whatever was the matter with Harry, his friend wasn't crazy. There had to be something real for Harry to suffer so. Ron didn't know what it was, but it was real.

Somehow Ron Weasley fell asleep again that night. He awoke to find Harry's bed still empty. His jaw tightened with concern and he wondered how to ask the questions he needed to ask. He wasn't as afraid anymore. Somehow he had put that part of him away, folded up like an old blanket.

He closed the door with steady hands, leaving another piece of his childhood in the room behind him.